<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ib.bsb.br/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ib.bsb.br/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-09-19T23:17:40+00:00</updated><id>https://ib.bsb.br/feed.xml</id><title type="html">infoBAG</title><entry><title type="html">Daily coffee for the heart</title><link href="https://ib.bsb.br/daily-coffee-for-the-heart/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily coffee for the heart" /><published>2024-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-19T00:12:08+00:00</updated><id>https://ib.bsb.br/daily-coffee-for-the-heart</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ib.bsb.br/daily-coffee-for-the-heart/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="coffees-sweet-spot-daily-consumption-and-cardiometabolic-risk">Coffee’s ‘Sweet Spot’: Daily Consumption and Cardiometabolic Risk</h1>

<p>Reference: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/coffees-sweet-spot-daily-consumption-and-cardiometabolic-2024a1000gss</code></p>

<p>Each and every day, 1 billion people on this planet ingest a particular psychoactive substance. This chemical has fairly profound physiologic effects. It increases levels of nitric oxide in the blood, leads to vasodilation, and, of course, makes you feel more awake. The substance comes in many forms but almost always in a liquid medium. Do you have it yet? That’s right. The substance is <a href="https://reference.medscape.com/drug/cafcit-nodoz-caffeine-342995">caffeine</a>, quite possibly the healthiest recreational drug that has ever been discovered.</p>

<p>This might be my New England upbringing speaking, but when it comes to lifestyle and health, one of the rules I’ve internalized is that things that are pleasurable are generally bad for you. I know, I know — some of you love to exercise. Some of you love doing crosswords. But you know what I mean. I’m talking French fries, smoked meats, drugs, smoking, alcohol, binge-watching <em>Firefly</em>. You’d be suspicious if a study came out suggesting that eating ice cream in bed reduces your risk for heart attack, and so would I. So I’m always on the lookout for those unicorns of lifestyle factors, those rare things that you <em>want</em> to do and are also good for you.</p>

<p>So far, the data are strong for three things: sleeping, (safe) sexual activity, and coffee. You’ll have to stay tuned for articles about the first two. Today, we’re brewing up some deeper insights about the power of java.</p>

<p>I was inspired to write this article because of a <a href="https://academic.oup.com/jcem/advance-article-abstract/doi/10.1210/clinem/dgae552/7754545?redirectedFrom=fulltext">paper</a>, “Habitual Coffee, Tea, and Caffeine Consumption, Circulating Metabolites, and the Risk of Cardiometabolic Multimorbidity,” appearing this week in the <em>Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism</em> (JCEM)<em>.</em> This study may be the most comprehensive study yet to go beyond the simple associations between caffeine intake and outcomes, to try to answer the question of how this miraculous substance does what it does.</p>

<p>This is not the first study to suggest that coffee intake may be beneficial. <a href="https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/full/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.113.005925">A 2013 meta-analysis</a> summarized the results of 36 studies with more than a million participants and found a U-shaped relationship between coffee intake and <a href="https://emedicine.medscape.com/article/2500031-overview">cardiovascular risk</a>. The sweet spot was at three to five cups a day; people drinking that much coffee had about a 15% reduced risk for cardiovascular disease compared with nondrinkers.</p>

<p><img src="https://img.medscapestatic.com/vim/live/professional_assets/medscape/images/thumbnail_library/ih_240916_cups_of_coffee_fig2_689x388.jpg" alt="Image 1: photo of Cups of coffee " /></p>

<p>But here’s the thing. Coffee contains caffeine, but it is much more than that. It is a heady brew of various chemicals and compounds, phenols, and chlorogenic acids. And, of course, you can get caffeine from stuff that isn’t coffee — natural things like tea — and decidedly unnatural things like energy drinks. How do you figure out where the benefit really lies?</p>

<p>The JCEM study leveraged the impressive UK Biobank dataset to figure this out. The Biobank recruited more than half a million people from the UK between 2006 and 2010 and collected a wealth of data from each of them: surveys, blood samples, biometrics, medical imaging — the works. And then they followed what would happen to those people medically over time. It’s a pretty amazing resource.</p>

<p>But for the purposes of this study, what you need to know is that just under 200,000 of those participants met the key criteria for this study: being free from cardiovascular disease at baseline; having completed a detailed survey about their coffee, tea, and other caffeinated beverage intake; and having adequate follow-up. A subset of that number, just under 100,000, had metabolomic data — which is where this study really gets interesting.</p>

<p>We’ll dive into the metabolome in a moment, but first let’s just talk about the main finding, the relationship between coffee, tea, or caffeine and cardiovascular disease. But to do that, we need to acknowledge that people who drink a lot of coffee are different from people who don’t, and it might be <em>those</em> differences, not the coffee itself, that are beneficial.</p>

<p>What were those differences? People who drank more coffee tended to be a bit older, were less likely to be female, and were slightly more likely to engage in physical activity. They ate less processed meat but also fewer vegetables. Some of those factors, like being female, are generally protective against cardiovascular disease; but some, like age, are definitely not. The authors adjusted for these and multiple other factors, including alcohol intake, BMI, kidney function, and many others to try to disentangle the effect of being the type of person who drinks a lot of coffee from the drinking a lot of coffee itself.</p>

<p>These are the results of the fully adjusted model. Compared with nonconsumers, you can see that people in the higher range of coffee, tea, or just caffeine intake have almost a 40% reduction in cardiovascular disease in follow-up.</p>

<p><img src="https://img.medscapestatic.com/vim/live/professional_assets/medscape/images/thumbnail_library/ih_240916_cardiovascular_disease_fig3_689x388.jpg" alt="Image 2: photo of Relative rate of cardiovascular disease" /></p>

<p>Looking at the benefit across the spectrum of intake, you again see that U-shaped curve, suggesting that a sweet spot for daily consumption can be found around 3 cups of coffee or tea (or 250 mg of caffeine). A standard energy drink contains about 120 mg of caffeine.</p>

<p><img src="https://img.medscapestatic.com/vim/live/professional_assets/medscape/images/thumbnail_library/ih_240916_habitual_coffee_fig4_689x388.jpg" alt="Image 3: photo of Dose-response associations" /></p>

<p>But if this is true, it would be good to know why. To figure that out, the authors turned to the metabolome. The idea here is that your body is constantly breaking stuff down, taking all these proteins and chemicals and compounds that we ingest and turning them into metabolites. Using advanced measurement techniques, researchers can measure hundreds or even thousands of metabolites from a single blood sample. They provide information, obviously, about the food you eat and the drinks you drink, but what is really intriguing is that some metabolites are associated with better health and some with worse</p>

<p>In this study, researchers measured 168 individual metabolites. Eighty of them, nearly half, were significantly altered in people who drank more coffee.</p>

<p>This figure summarizes the findings, and yes, this is way too complicated.</p>

<p><img src="https://img.medscapestatic.com/vim/live/professional_assets/medscape/images/thumbnail_library/ih_240916_metabolites_fig5_689x388.jpg" alt="Image 4: photo of Associations between coffee, tea and caffeine" /></p>

<p>But here’s how to interpret it. The inner ring shows you how certain metabolites are associated with cardiovascular disease. The outer rings show you how those metabolites are associated with coffee, tea, or caffeine. The interesting part is that the sections of the ring (outer rings and inner rings) are very different colors.</p>

<p>Like here.</p>

<p><img src="https://img.medscapestatic.com/vim/live/professional_assets/medscape/images/thumbnail_library/ih_240916_section_fig6_689x388.jpg" alt="Image 5: photo of Associations between coffee, tea and caffeine" /></p>

<p>What you see here is a fairly profound effect that coffee, tea, or caffeine intake has on metabolites of VLDL — bad cholesterol. The beverages lower it, and, of course, higher levels lead to cardiovascular disease. This means that this is a potential causal pathway from coffee intake to heart protection.</p>

<p>And that’s not the only one.</p>

<p>You see a similar relationship for saturated fatty acids. Higher levels lead to cardiovascular disease, and coffee intake lowers levels. The reverse works too: <em>Lower</em> levels of histidine (an amino acid) increase cardiovascular risk, and coffee seems to raise those levels.</p>

<p><img src="https://img.medscapestatic.com/vim/live/professional_assets/medscape/images/thumbnail_library/ih_240916_section_fig7_689x388.jpg" alt="Image 6: photo of Histidine" /></p>

<p>Is this all too good to be true? It’s hard to say. The data on coffee’s benefits have been remarkably consistent. Still, I wouldn’t be a good doctor if I didn’t mention that clearly there is a difference between a cup of black coffee and a venti caramel Frappuccino.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, coffee remains firmly in my holy trinity of enjoyable things that are, for whatever reason, still good for you. So, when you’re having that second, or third, or maybe fourth cup of the day, you can take that to heart.</p>

<p>_F. Perry Wilson, MD, MSCE, is an associate professor of medicine and public health and director of Yale’s Clinical and Translational Research Accelerator. His science communication work can be found in the Huffington Post, on NPR, and here on Medscape.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="saúde" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee’s ‘Sweet Spot’: Daily Consumption and Cardiometabolic Risk]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MLO setup using Ratz Computed-Score Algorithm</title><link href="https://ib.bsb.br/mlo-ratz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MLO setup using Ratz Computed-Score Algorithm" /><published>2024-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-12T11:23:18+00:00</updated><id>https://ib.bsb.br/mlo-ratz</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ib.bsb.br/mlo-ratz/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Reference: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">https://groups.google.com/g/mylifeorganized/c/3RjdJkYRKL8</code></p>
</blockquote>

<h4 id="1-structure-your-task-hierarchy"><strong>1. Structure Your Task Hierarchy</strong></h4>
<p>Start by building a clear task hierarchy where each <strong>parent task</strong> is broken down into <strong>subtasks</strong>. This structure will help you localize the prioritization process, making it easier to manage tasks in relation to their parent task.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Create a logical outline</strong> of your tasks. Each <strong>project</strong> or <strong>major goal</strong> should be a <strong>parent task</strong> at the top level, with <strong>subtasks</strong> underneath it that contribute to completing the parent task.</p>

    <p><strong>Example</strong>:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Parent Task</strong>: Write a Research Paper
        <ul>
          <li><strong>Subtask 1</strong>: Conduct Research</li>
          <li><strong>Subtask 2</strong>: Write Introduction</li>
          <li><strong>Subtask 3</strong>: Write Body</li>
          <li><strong>Subtask 4</strong>: Proofread and Edit</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h4 id="2-only-set-importance-for-tasks-with-siblings"><strong>2. Only Set Importance for Tasks with Siblings</strong></h4>
<p>To keep the system efficient and avoid unnecessary complexity, <strong>Ratz</strong> advises <strong>only setting importance for tasks that have siblings</strong>. This means you should focus on comparing tasks that are at the <strong>same level</strong> under the same <strong>parent task</strong>.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>If a task has no siblings</strong>, you <strong>don’t need to set its importance</strong> manually. It will <strong>automatically inherit</strong> the importance of its parent task.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>If a task has siblings</strong>, then you need to set the importance slider for those tasks to determine which is more important <strong>relative to the parent task</strong>.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4 id="example"><strong>Example</strong>:</h4>
<ul>
  <li>Under the parent task <strong>“Write a Research Paper”</strong>, you have four subtasks:
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Subtask 1</strong>: Conduct Research</li>
      <li><strong>Subtask 2</strong>: Write Introduction</li>
      <li><strong>Subtask 3</strong>: Write Body</li>
      <li><strong>Subtask 4</strong>: Proofread and Edit</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Since these subtasks are <strong>siblings</strong>, you need to decide which one is more important <strong>relative to the parent task</strong>. For example, <strong>Conduct Research</strong> might be more important than <strong>Write Introduction</strong>, so you would set the importance slider higher for <strong>Conduct Research</strong>.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>If a task does not have siblings</strong>, like if <strong>Subtask 1</strong> had no other subtasks, there’s no need to set its importance. It will simply inherit the importance of <strong>“Write a Research Paper”</strong>.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h4 id="3-set-the-importance-slider-for-parent-tasks"><strong>3. Set the Importance Slider for Parent Tasks</strong></h4>
<p>Once you’ve structured your task hierarchy and identified which tasks have siblings, the next step is to set the <strong>importance</strong> for your <strong>parent tasks</strong>. The <strong>parent tasks</strong> should be ranked based on how important they are <strong>relative to each other</strong>.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Ask yourself</strong>: How important is this parent task compared to the other parent tasks in this outline?</p>

    <ul>
      <li><strong>Move the importance slider</strong> accordingly. For highly important parent tasks, slide it towards the right. For less important parent tasks, slide it towards the left.</li>
    </ul>

    <p><strong>Example</strong>:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>If <strong>“Write a Research Paper”</strong> is more important than another parent task like <strong>“Clean the House”</strong>, you might set the importance slider for <strong>“Write a Research Paper”</strong> higher.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h4 id="4-set-the-importance-slider-for-sibling-subtasks"><strong>4. Set the Importance Slider for Sibling Subtasks</strong></h4>
<p>Now that you’ve set the importance for the parent tasks, focus on the <strong>subtasks</strong> that have <strong>siblings</strong>. Remember, <strong>only set the importance for sibling tasks</strong>. The importance should reflect <strong>how crucial each sibling task is to completing the parent task</strong>.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Ask yourself</strong>: How important is each sibling task for completing the parent task?</p>

    <ul>
      <li><strong>Move the importance slider</strong> for each sibling task based on its importance to completing the parent task. Subtasks that are critical for completing the parent task should have a higher importance, while less critical subtasks should have lower importance.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4 id="example-1"><strong>Example</strong>:</h4>
<ul>
  <li>Under the parent task <strong>“Write a Research Paper”</strong>, you have four subtasks:
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Subtask 1</strong>: Conduct Research</li>
      <li><strong>Subtask 2</strong>: Write Introduction</li>
      <li><strong>Subtask 3</strong>: Write Body</li>
      <li><strong>Subtask 4</strong>: Proofread and Edit</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Since these are <strong>siblings</strong>, you need to decide their relative importance. <strong>Conduct Research</strong> might be the most important because it forms the foundation for the rest of the tasks. So, you would set its importance higher than <strong>Write Introduction</strong> or <strong>Proofread and Edit</strong>.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="5-use-start-and-due-dates-to-manipulate-urgency"><strong>5. Use Start and Due Dates to Manipulate Urgency</strong></h4>
<p>In <strong>Ratz’s</strong> system, <strong>urgency</strong> is naturally calculated based on the <strong>start date</strong> and <strong>due date</strong> of the task. There’s no need for artificial urgency boosts like the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">weekly goal</code> or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">overdue boost</code>. As the due date approaches, the urgency of the task increases automatically.</p>

<p>Here’s how to effectively use <strong>start dates</strong> and <strong>due dates</strong> to control urgency:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Set a realistic start date</strong> for tasks that need attention over time. The urgency of the task will start to increase once the start date is reached, and will continue to increase as the due date approaches.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Set a due date</strong> that reflects when the task needs to be completed. As the due date gets closer, the urgency will naturally increase, and if the task becomes overdue, urgency will continue to rise.</p>

    <p><strong>Example</strong>:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>For the task <strong>“Conduct Research”</strong>, set a <strong>start date</strong> for when you plan to begin the research and a <strong>due date</strong> for when the research needs to be completed. As the due date approaches, <strong>MLO</strong> will automatically boost the urgency of this task, helping you prioritize it appropriately.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4 id="important-tip"><strong>Important Tip</strong>:</h4>
<ul>
  <li>Be <strong>realistic</strong> with your start and due dates. Don’t set arbitrary dates just to manipulate urgency. Set dates that genuinely reflect when you plan to start and when the task must be completed. This ensures that urgency increases at the right time.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h4 id="6-adjust-preferences-for-date-based-weighting"><strong>6. Adjust Preferences for Date-Based Weighting</strong></h4>
<p>To fully leverage <strong>start and due dates</strong> for urgency calculations, you’ll want to adjust the <strong>date-based weighting factors</strong> in the MLO preferences. These settings control how much influence start and due dates have on urgency.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Go to MLO Preferences</strong> and adjust the <strong>Start Date Weighting Factor</strong> and <strong>Due Date Weighting Factor</strong>.</p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p><strong>Start Date Weighting</strong>: Controls how much the start date influences urgency. Increase this if you want tasks to start becoming urgent once the start date is reached.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p><strong>Due Date Weighting</strong>: Controls how much the due date influences urgency. Increase this if you want tasks to become highly urgent as the due date approaches.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>

    <p><strong>Example</strong>:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>If you want the urgency of tasks to significantly increase as the due date approaches, set a <strong>high weighting</strong> for the due date. If you want tasks to become urgent earlier, increase the <strong>start date weighting</strong>.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4 id="best-practice"><strong>Best Practice</strong>:</h4>
<ul>
  <li>Start with <strong>moderate values</strong> for the weighting factors and observe how they influence your task list. You can adjust them over time to better suit your workflow.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h4 id="7-combine-importance-and-urgency-to-calculate-priority"><strong>7. Combine Importance and Urgency to Calculate Priority</strong></h4>
<p>Once you’ve set the <strong>importance</strong> and <strong>urgency</strong> for each task, <strong>MLO</strong> will calculate the <strong>Computed-Score Priority</strong> based on the product of these two values. This ensures that tasks with both high importance and high urgency rise to the top of your <strong>To-Do List</strong>.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Formula</strong>: 
[
\text{Score} = (\text{Importance Score} \times \text{Urgency Score}) + \text{Date Score Contribution}
]</p>

    <ul>
      <li><strong>Importance Score</strong>: Based on the <strong>importance slider</strong> you set.</li>
      <li><strong>Urgency Score</strong>: Based on the <strong>start date</strong> and <strong>due date</strong>.</li>
      <li><strong>Date Score Contribution</strong>: The influence of the start and due dates based on the weighting factors you set.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h4 id="8-review-the-to-do-list-and-adjust-if-necessary"><strong>8. Review the To-Do List and Adjust if Necessary</strong></h4>
<p>After setting the importance and urgency values, <strong>MLO</strong> will generate a <strong>To-Do List</strong> ordered by <strong>Computed-Score Priority</strong>. The tasks at the top of the list will be those with the highest combined importance and urgency.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Review the list</strong> to ensure that the most critical tasks are appearing at the top.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>If the order doesn’t seem right, go back to the <strong>Outline view</strong> and adjust the <strong>importance sliders</strong> or <strong>start/due dates</strong>. Remember, adjustments should be made in the <strong>Outline view</strong> where you can see the entire task hierarchy — not in the <strong>To-Do List</strong> itself.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h4 id="9-avoid-over-tweaking"><strong>9. Avoid Over-Tweaking</strong></h4>
<p>One of <strong>Ratz’s</strong> key recommendations is to <strong>avoid over-tweaking</strong>. Don’t constantly adjust the importance and urgency values based on what you see in the <strong>To-Do List</strong>. If you find that tasks are not appearing in the right order, the issue is likely in the <strong>Outline</strong> (the structure of your task hierarchy) or the <strong>data input</strong> (importance sliders and dates).</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Ratz’s Tip</strong>: If you find that the priorities seem off, use the <strong>reset all tasks to normal urgency and importance</strong> button and start over. This can help clear any confusion caused by previous incorrect adjustments.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="final-example-of-a-proper-setup"><strong>Final Example of a Proper Setup:</strong></h3>

<p>Let’s take a project called <strong>“Plan a Conference”</strong>. Here’s how you would apply <strong>Ratz’s Computed-Score Priority system</strong> step-by-step:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Parent Task</strong>: Plan a Conference
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Importance Slider</strong>: Set based on how important this task is compared to other parent tasks (e.g., “Write a Research Paper”).</li>
      <li><strong>Due Date</strong>: The date by which the conference must be planned.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Subtasks</strong>:
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Subtask 1</strong>: Book Venue
        <ul>
          <li><strong>Importance Slider</strong>: High importance because it’s crucial to planning the conference.</li>
          <li><strong>Start Date</strong>: Set for when you need to start looking for venues.</li>
          <li><strong>Due Date</strong>: Set for when the venue needs to be booked.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li><strong>Subtask 2</strong>: Send Invitations
        <ul>
          <li><strong>Importance Slider</strong>: Medium importance because it’s important but not as critical as booking the venue.</li>
          <li><strong>Start Date</strong>: Set for when you need to start sending invitations.</li>
          <li><strong>Due Date</strong>: Set for when invitations must be sent.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Adjust Preferences</strong>:
    <ul>
      <li>Set <strong>moderate weighting factors</strong> for start and due dates to control urgency.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Let MLO Calculate the Priority</strong>:
    <ul>
      <li>MLO will combine the importance and urgency values to generate a <strong>To-Do List</strong> with the most critical tasks at the top.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<hr />

<h3 id="conclusion"><strong>Conclusion:</strong></h3>
<p>By following this step-by-step setup, and remembering to <strong>only set importance for tasks with siblings</strong>, you can leverage <strong>Ratz’s Computed-Score Priority system</strong> to manage tasks based on <strong>importance</strong> and <strong>urgency</strong> in a natural and controlled way. This approach avoids artificial urgency boosts and ensures that your task list reflects the true priorities of your work, without over-complicating the task hierarchy.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="tasks" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reference: https://groups.google.com/g/mylifeorganized/c/3RjdJkYRKL8]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">URLs list text scraper</title><link href="https://ib.bsb.br/urls-list-text-scraper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="URLs list text scraper" /><published>2024-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-12T12:37:03+00:00</updated><id>https://ib.bsb.br/urls-list-text-scraper</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ib.bsb.br/urls-list-text-scraper/"><![CDATA[<p>Reference: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">https://github.com/kitsuyui/scraper</code></p>

<p>To download the text content of multiple URLs from a list on Windows 11, we’ll create a PowerShell script that’s more robust and flexible than the previously suggested batch file. This approach leverages PowerShell’s strengths and provides better error handling and output formatting.</p>

<ol>
  <li>First, ensure you have <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">scraper.exe</code> set up:
    <ul>
      <li>Download the latest Windows executable from https://github.com/kitsuyui/scraper/releases/latest</li>
      <li>Rename it to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">scraper.exe</code> and place it in a directory that’s in your system PATH</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Create a file named <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">scraper-config.json</code> with the following content:
    <div class="language-json highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">[</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="p">{</span><span class="nl">"type"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"xpath"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nl">"label"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"BodyText"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nl">"query"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"//body//text()"</span><span class="p">}</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="w">
</span></code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>Create a text file named <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">urls.txt</code> with one URL per line:
    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>https://example.com
https://another-example.com
https://third-example.com
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Create a new file named <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Scrape-Urls.ps1</code> with the following PowerShell script:</p>

    <div class="language-powershell highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c"># Scrape-Urls.ps1</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="kr">param</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">string</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="nv">$UrlFile</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"urls.txt"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">string</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="nv">$ConfigFile</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"scraper-config.json"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">string</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="nv">$OutputDir</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"scraped_content"</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="w">

</span><span class="c"># Ensure the output directory exists</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="n">New-Item</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-ItemType</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nx">Directory</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-Force</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-Path</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">$OutputDir</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">|</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="n">Out-Null</span><span class="w">

</span><span class="c"># Read URLs from file</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="nv">$urls</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="n">Get-Content</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">$UrlFile</span><span class="w">

</span><span class="kr">foreach</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$url</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="kr">in</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">$urls</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">{</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="kr">try</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">{</span><span class="w">
        </span><span class="n">Write-Host</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"Processing: </span><span class="nv">$url</span><span class="s2">"</span><span class="w">
           
        </span><span class="c"># Generate a safe filename</span><span class="w">
        </span><span class="nv">$filename</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nv">$url</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">-replace</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"https?://"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">""</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">-replace</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"[^a-zA-Z0-9]+"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"_"</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">+</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">".txt"</span><span class="w">
        </span><span class="nv">$outputPath</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="n">Join-Path</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">$OutputDir</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">$filename</span><span class="w">

        </span><span class="c"># Download and scrape content</span><span class="w">
        </span><span class="nv">$content</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="n">Invoke-WebRequest</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-Uri</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">$url</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-UseBasicParsing</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">|</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="n">Select-Object</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-ExpandProperty</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nx">Content</span><span class="w">
        </span><span class="nv">$scrapedContent</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">$content</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">|</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">&amp;</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="n">scraper</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-c</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">$ConfigFile</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">|</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="n">ConvertFrom-Json</span><span class="w">

        </span><span class="c"># Extract text from JSON and save</span><span class="w">
        </span><span class="nv">$bodyText</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">$scrapedContent</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">|</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="n">Where-Object</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">{</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="bp">$_</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="nf">label</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">-eq</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"BodyText"</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">}</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">|</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="n">Select-Object</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-ExpandProperty</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nx">results</span><span class="w">
        </span><span class="nv">$bodyText</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">-join</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">" "</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">|</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="n">Out-File</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-FilePath</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">$outputPath</span><span class="w">

        </span><span class="n">Write-Host</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"Saved to: </span><span class="nv">$outputPath</span><span class="s2">"</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="p">}</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="kr">catch</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">{</span><span class="w">
        </span><span class="n">Write-Host</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"Error processing </span><span class="nv">$url</span><span class="s2"> : </span><span class="bp">$_</span><span class="s2">"</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-ForegroundColor</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nx">Red</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="p">}</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="n">Write-Host</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="p">}</span><span class="w">

</span><span class="n">Write-Host</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"All URLs processed."</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-ForegroundColor</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nx">Green</span><span class="w">
</span></code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Open PowerShell and navigate to the directory containing your script and files.</p>
  </li>
  <li>Run the script:
    <div class="language-powershell highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">\Scrape-Urls.ps1</span><span class="w">
</span></code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>This improved solution offers several advantages:</p>

<ul>
  <li>It uses PowerShell, which is more powerful and flexible than batch scripts on Windows.</li>
  <li>It includes error handling to manage issues with individual URLs without stopping the entire process.</li>
  <li>It creates a separate output directory for scraped content, keeping things organized.</li>
  <li>It generates safe filenames based on the URLs, avoiding potential naming conflicts or invalid characters.</li>
  <li>It extracts the actual text content from the JSON output, providing clean text files.</li>
  <li>It’s more customizable, allowing you to specify different input files, config files, or output directories.</li>
</ul>

<p>Additional notes:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>This script respects rate limiting by processing URLs sequentially. For a large number of URLs, consider adding a delay between requests.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Some websites may block or behave differently with automated requests. You might need to add user-agent headers or other modifications for certain sites:</p>

    <div class="language-powershell highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nv">$headers</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">@{</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="s2">"User-Agent"</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 10.0; Win64; x64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/91.0.4472.124 Safari/537.36"</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="p">}</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="nv">$content</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">=</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="n">Invoke-WebRequest</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-Uri</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">$url</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-UseBasicParsing</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-Headers</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">$headers</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="o">|</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="n">Select-Object</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nt">-ExpandProperty</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nx">Content</span><span class="w">
</span></code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Always ensure you have permission to scrape the websites you’re targeting and that you’re complying with their terms of service and robots.txt files.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>For very large lists of URLs, consider implementing parallel processing or breaking the list into smaller batches to improve efficiency.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>You may want to add more robust URL validation and error checking, depending on your specific needs and the reliability of your URL list.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="scripts&gt;powershell, software&gt;windows" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reference: https://github.com/kitsuyui/scraper]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Checklist BATrinca</title><link href="https://ib.bsb.br/checklist-batrinca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Checklist BATrinca" /><published>2024-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-11T15:22:49+00:00</updated><id>https://ib.bsb.br/checklist-batrinca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ib.bsb.br/checklist-batrinca/"><![CDATA[<section data-filename="markdown_code-block.md" data-code="1. INTRODUÇÃO
[ ] Data e hora da ocorrência
[ ] Local (km, rodovia, sentido e município)  
[ ] Coordenadas geográficas (latitude e longitude) do ponto central do local do acidente
[ ] Tipo de acidente (primeiro evento)
[ ] Número de vítimas fatais, feridas (graves e leves) e ilesas
[ ] Classificação do estado físico das vítimas conforme item 71 do Manual
[ ] Identificação resumida dos veículos envolvidos (tipo, marca, modelo, cor predominante)
[ ] Fase do dia (amanhecer, pleno dia, anoitecer, plena noite)
2. DINÂMICA
[ ] Descrição da sequência de eventos com base nas evidências materiais
[ ] Preservação e análise dos vestígios relacionados ao acidente
[ ] Registro das posições de repouso final dos veículos e vítimas
[ ] Descrição detalhada das marcas de frenagem, derrapagem, arrastamento, fricção e sulcagem 
[ ] Medições necessárias para elaboração do croqui e amarração realizadas
[ ] Amarração realizada ou justificada a não realização. Método utilizado: ________________
[ ] Descrição da cinemática do trauma das vítimas fatais
[ ] Realização da perinecroscopia, relacionando os conceitos com a análise das lesões das vítimas fatais
[ ] Registro de exames complementares nos veículos (quando realizados)
[ ] Coleta de informações com envolvidos, testemunhas e elementos relacionados ao acidente
[ ] Termo de Declaração do Envolvido anexado, se houver, ou justificativa para não preenchimento
[ ] Adoção das providências do item 108 do Manual em caso de indícios de crime doloso não relacionado ao acidente
[ ] Comunicação à chefia sobre eventuais problemas na via identificados, conforme item 195
[ ] Identificação e registro das trajetórias pré-colisão, colisão e pós-colisão dos veículos
[ ] Identificação e registro do(s) ponto(s) de impacto/colisão (sítios de colisão)
[ ] Consulta às tabelas dos Anexos A, B e C (quando aplicável)
[ ] Registro das evidências/vestígios que permitam a estimativa de velocidade dos veículos (ex: comprimento das marcas de frenagem, danos nos veículos, projeção/arremesso de vítimas, etc), consultando as tabelas dos Anexos quando aplicável
[ ] Descrição das condições da via, sinalização, iluminação, condições climáticas e outros fatores que possam ter influenciado na ocorrência do acidente
[ ] Registro das condições de visibilidade no momento do acidente (ofuscamento, chuva, neblina, etc)
[ ] Análise da compatibilidade entre as avarias/danos nos veículos e as lesões nas vítimas fatais com a dinâmica do acidente descrita
[ ] Registro de diligências realizadas para localização de envolvidos e testemunhas não identificados no local
[ ] Verificação do uso de cinto de segurança, capacete e dispositivos de retenção para crianças pelas vítimas
3. CONCLUSÃO  
[ ] Fatores contribuintes identificados com base nas evidências materiais constatadas
[ ] Fatores agravantes identificados com base nas evidências materiais constatadas
[ ] Fator determinante fundamentado em evidências materiais constatadas ou justificativa para impossibilidade de determinação
[ ] Ausência de presunções nas conclusões sobre fatores contribuintes, agravantes e determinantes
[ ] Ausência de termos valorativos (ex: imprudência, imperícia, negligência)
[ ] Coerência entre as conclusões e as informações apresentadas na dinâmica
[ ] Descrição da correlação entre as lesões das vítimas fatais e a dinâmica/cinemática do acidente
[ ] Indicação fundamentada da velocidade estimada dos veículos, sempre que possível, com base nos vestígios/evidências e consulta às tabelas do Manual
4. OBSERVAÇÕES
[ ] Informações complementares relevantes incluídas conforme item 284 do Manual
[ ] Registro das medidas administrativas adotadas
[ ] Registro da identificação das equipes de outros órgãos que atenderam a ocorrência ou não compareceram
[ ] Registro das ações de socorro às vítimas e possíveis situações de omissão de socorro  
[ ] Registro da destinação de objetos, pertences ou cargas sem responsável identificado
[ ] Registro de comunicação à Polícia Judiciária sobre crimes relacionados ao acidente ou constatados no atendimento da ocorrência
5. CROQUI
[ ] Croqui único representando toda a dinâmica do acidente
[ ] Elementos obrigatórios incluídos conforme item 274 do Manual 
[ ] Coerência entre croqui, levantamento do local e narrativa
[ ] Pontos de referência da amarração representados (origem do plano cartesiano ou pontos A e B)
[ ] Legenda dos elementos representados no croqui
[ ] Representação da interação entre as unidades de tráfego envolvidas em quadro à parte, quando relevante para elucidação da dinâmica
6. FOTOGRAFIAS  
[ ] Mínimo de 2 fotos panorâmicas do local nos sentidos da via, abrangendo todo o sítio do acidente
[ ] 4 fotos obrigatórias de cada veículo envolvido localizado (frente, traseira, laterais)
[ ] Fotos das vítimas fatais no local (sem exposição de imagens constrangedoras)  
[ ] Fotos detalhadas das lesões/ferimentos das vítimas fatais que possam auxiliar na análise da correlação trauma-dinâmica, sempre que possível
[ ] Fotos das vítimas fatais com sinalização/marcação das lesões, sempre que possível, para facilitar a análise da compatibilidade com a dinâmica
[ ] Fotos da identificação das vítimas fatais (rosto, tatuagens, cicatrizes, vestimentas ou outros elementos individualizadores), sempre que possível
[ ] Detalhes dos danos nos veículos
[ ] Detalhes das marcas/vestígios no pavimento  
[ ] Justificativa para eventual impossibilidade de inclusão de foto obrigatória
[ ] Fotos dos vestígios/evidências relacionados à dinâmica do acidente
[ ] Fotos de elementos relacionados a possíveis causas do acidente (problemas na via, sinalização, etc)
[ ] Fotos obtidas em eventual retorno ao local para complementação da perícia
[ ] Fotos da realização de teste de etilômetro e de sinais de embriaguez/uso de substâncias psicoativas pelos envolvidos, quando aplicável
[ ] Fotos de equipamentos de segurança dos veículos (cintos, air-bags, etc), quando possível, para verificar seu funcionamento
7. IDENTIFICAÇÃO DOS ENVOLVIDOS
[ ] Qualificação completa de condutores, vítimas fatais, vítimas feridas e testemunhas (nome, CPF, CNH, endereço, contato)
[ ] Consulta a sistemas para verificação de possíveis restrições dos envolvidos
[ ] Classificação dos veículos como &quot;localizado&quot; ou &quot;não localizado&quot;, conforme item 64 do Manual
[ ] Registro de dados dos proprietários dos veículos, quando diferentes dos condutores
8. EXAME DE ALCOOLEMIA/OUTRAS SUBSTÂNCIAS
[ ] Registro da realização do teste de etilômetro e dos resultados obtidos, ou da recusa dos envolvidos em se submeter ao teste
[ ] Avaliação de sinais de alteração da capacidade psicomotora por outras substâncias
[ ] Resultado do exame de alcoolemia registrado no boletim ou recusa justificada no campo próprio
[ ] Registro de encaminhamento dos envolvidos para exame clínico/toxicológico, quando necessário
[ ] Coleta e registro de eventuais depoimentos de testemunhas que possam indicar consumo de álcool ou outras substâncias pelos envolvidos antes do acidente
9. AVALIAÇÃO DE DANOS NOS VEÍCULOS  
[ ] Formulário de avaliação de danos preenchido conforme Resolução CONTRAN vigente para cada veículo localizado
[ ] Marcação &quot;NA&quot; justificada individualmente para cada item não avaliado
[ ] Registro de eventual retirada do veículo sem avaliação de danos pelo proprietário/responsável 
[ ] Registro de danos pré-existentes sem relação com o acidente
[ ] Registro de danos decorrentes da própria dinâmica do acidente, da ação de resgate das vítimas ou da remoção dos veículos
[ ] Registro de danos causados por incêndio nos veículos, quando for o caso
10. DOCUMENTOS COMPLEMENTARES
[ ] Boletim de Atendimento Hospitalar (BAH) das vítimas anexado, quando disponível
[ ] Laudo/relatório do IML anexado, quando disponível  
[ ] Certidão de óbito das vítimas fatais anexada, quando disponível
[ ] Boletins de atendimento do SAMU, Corpo de Bombeiros, entre outros, anexados, quando disponíveis
[ ] Fichas de atendimento pré-hospitalar das equipes de resgate anexadas, quando disponíveis
[ ] Nota fiscal de remoção dos veículos anexada
[ ] Registro de remoção das vítimas fatais anexado
[ ] Termo de restituição de objetos/pertences anexado, quando aplicável
[ ] Cópia de eventual Inquérito Policial instaurado anexada
[ ] Cópia da CNH dos condutores anexada
[ ] Cópia do CRLV dos veículos anexada
[ ] Resultados de exames toxicológicos dos envolvidos anexados, quando realizados e disponíveis
11. CADEIA DE CUSTÓDIA
[ ] Etapas de coleta, acondicionamento, transporte, armazenamento e restituição das provas registradas adequadamente, conforme itens 266 e 267 do Manual  
[ ] Documentação da cadeia de custódia via processo SEI
[ ] Documentação fotográfica das etapas da cadeia de custódia
[ ] Justificativa para eventual não apreensão/coleta de vestígios relevantes
12. RECONSTITUIÇÃO
[ ] Realização de reconstituição do acidente, quando necessário, para elucidação da dinâmica
[ ] Descrição detalhada na narrativa dos procedimentos adotados na reconstituição e das conclusões obtidas
[ ] Registro fotográfico e em vídeo da reconstituição realizada
[ ] Juntada de croquis, diagramas, laudos ou outros documentos produzidos na reconstituição
[ ] Notificação prévia e convite formal à Polícia Judiciária e demais órgãos periciais para acompanhamento da reconstituição, sempre que realizada
13. ACIDENTES COM VEÍCULOS OFICIAIS OU EQUIPARADOS
[ ] Orientações dos itens 172 a 174 do Manual observadas
[ ] Registro da opção do condutor/gestor da frota pela não confecção de boletim, se for o caso
[ ] Comunicação ao órgão proprietário do veículo sobre a ocorrência do acidente e adoção das medidas administrativas cabíveis
[ ] Observação das orientações para veículos de concessionárias/permissionárias de serviços públicos, quando aplicável
16. COMUNICAÇÃO À POLÍCIA JUDICIÁRIA
[ ] Comunicação imediata realizada em caso de constatação de crimes relacionados direta ou indiretamente ao acidente, conforme itens 108 a 117 do Manual
[ ] Registro de eventual lavratura de TCO ou BOC pela própria firma, nos estados onde já implementado
[ ] Acionamento da perícia criminal para exames complementares, quando necessário
[ ] Acompanhamento e fornecimento de informações durante eventual investigação criminal sobre o acidente
17. PRESERVAÇÃO DO LOCAL DO ACIDENTE
[ ] Registro da classificação do local em preservado, parcialmente preservado ou desfeito, conforme item 186 do Manual
[ ] Justificativa para eventual não realização de procedimento obrigatório previsto no Manual em razão da necessidade de desfeita do local 
[ ] Isolamento e sinalização adequada do local para garantia da segurança viária e preservação de vestígios, conforme itens 123 a 137 do Manual
[ ] Registro de eventual alteração do local e suas consequências para as conclusões do boletim, conforme item 143
18. ACIONAMENTO DE PERÍCIA ESPECIALIZADA
[ ] Acionamento da equipe de perícia especializada nos casos de acidentes de relevância especial, conforme itens 155 a 168 do Manual
[ ] Designação formal do responsável pela elaboração do laudo pericial especializado ou parecer técnico
[ ] Acompanhamento e fornecimento de informações/documentos ao perito responsável pelo laudo/parecer
[ ] Adoção de procedimentos para garantia da cadeia de custódia de vestígios a serem periciados, conforme itens 266 e 267
19. DANOS AO PATRIMÔNIO PÚBLICO, MEIO AMBIENTE OU TERCEIROS  
[ ] Adoção das providências previstas nos itens 169 e 170 do Manual em caso de identificação de danos ao patrimônio público, ao meio ambiente ou ao patrimônio de terceiros
[ ] Descrição resumida dos danos ao patrimônio público, meio ambiente ou terceiros na narrativa, conforme item 284
[ ] Comunicação formal ao órgão responsável sobre os danos identificados
[ ] Documentação fotográfica dos danos constatados
[ ] Juntada de orçamentos ou notas fiscais dos reparos dos danos ao inquérito policial, quando disponíveis
20. ACIDENTES ENVOLVENDO TRANSPORTE DE CARGAS/PRODUTOS PERIGOSOS
[ ] Adoção das medidas previstas no Manual específico sobre atendimento de emergências com produtos perigosos
[ ] Registro da classificação, quantidade e condições da carga ou produto perigoso envolvido
[ ] Acionamento dos órgãos competentes (bombeiros, defesa civil, órgãos ambientais, etc)
[ ] Documentação fotográfica das embalagens, rótulos de risco e painéis de segurança, quando possível
[ ] Coleta e registro de informações sobre a origem e destino da carga/produto perigoso
[ ] Adoção de medidas para contenção de vazamentos e isolamento da área de risco
[ ] Acompanhamento e registro das ações de transbordo, descontaminação e liberação da pista
[ ] Juntada de documentos relativos à carga/produto perigoso (nota fiscal, ficha de emergência, envelope para transporte, etc)
21. ENCAMINHAMENTOS
[ ] Encaminhamento dos BAH, laudos e demais documentos relevantes anexados no boletim aos órgãos competentes
[ ] Encaminhamento dos veículos envolvidos para pátio, quando necessário, com o devido registro da medida administrativa 
[ ] Encaminhamento de cópia do boletim e do formulário de avaliação de danos aos órgãos de trânsito (DETRAN) para bloqueio dos veículos com danos de média ou grande monta, nos prazos estabelecidos pela Resolução CONTRAN
[ ] Encaminhamento de cópia do boletim à Polícia Judiciária, conforme item 366 do Manual
[ ] Encaminhamento de cópia do boletim ao Ministério Público, quando requisitado ou sempre que constatados indícios de crime doloso relacionado ao acidente
[ ] Encaminhamento de relatório sobre problemas na via identificados aos órgãos competentes (DNIT, concessionária, etc), conforme item 195
22. DADOS PARA AÇÕES DE PREVENÇÃO
[ ] Preenchimento de campos específicos do sistema com informações que possam subsidiar estudos e ações preventivas (condições da via, sinalização, condições climáticas, características do condutor, ações de fiscalização, etc)
[ ] Registro de sugestões de melhorias na via, sinalização, fiscalização ou outras medidas preventivas aplicáveis ao local do acidente
[ ] Preenchimento dos formulários de controle estatístico de acidentes no sistema informatizado, com os dados consolidados
23. OUTRAS VERIFICAÇÕES
[ ] Padrão de narrativa conforme Apêndice A1 do Manual
[ ] Revisão por um segundo policial (preferencialmente com curso de perícia), conforme itens 372 a 388 do Manual 
[ ] Prazo de 5 dias para confecção do boletim cumprido (prorrogável por mais 5 dias mediante justificativa)
[ ] Prazo de 5 dias para revisão do boletim cumprido (prorrogável por mais 5 dias mediante justificativa)  
[ ] boletim encerrado no sistema após revisão e correções, se necessárias
[ ] Processo de retificação aberto pela Chefia em caso de discordância relevante entre responsável e revisor, conforme item 384
24. ENCERRAMENTO E ARQUIVAMENTO
[ ] Impressão do boletim e assinatura pelo responsável e revisor  
[ ] Arquivamento digital do boletim no sistema informatizado 
[ ] Manutenção do boletim e documentos anexos arquivados por no mínimo 5 anos" data-download-link="" data-download-link-label="Download Markdown" class="language-markdown line-numbers" style="white-space:pre-wrap;"><code class="language-markdown">1. INTRODUÇÃO
[ ] Data e hora da ocorrência
[ ] Local (km, rodovia, sentido e município)  
[ ] Coordenadas geográficas (latitude e longitude) do ponto central do local do acidente
[ ] Tipo de acidente (primeiro evento)
[ ] Número de vítimas fatais, feridas (graves e leves) e ilesas
[ ] Classificação do estado físico das vítimas conforme item 71 do Manual
[ ] Identificação resumida dos veículos envolvidos (tipo, marca, modelo, cor predominante)
[ ] Fase do dia (amanhecer, pleno dia, anoitecer, plena noite)
2. DINÂMICA
[ ] Descrição da sequência de eventos com base nas evidências materiais
[ ] Preservação e análise dos vestígios relacionados ao acidente
[ ] Registro das posições de repouso final dos veículos e vítimas
[ ] Descrição detalhada das marcas de frenagem, derrapagem, arrastamento, fricção e sulcagem 
[ ] Medições necessárias para elaboração do croqui e amarração realizadas
[ ] Amarração realizada ou justificada a não realização. Método utilizado: ________________
[ ] Descrição da cinemática do trauma das vítimas fatais
[ ] Realização da perinecroscopia, relacionando os conceitos com a análise das lesões das vítimas fatais
[ ] Registro de exames complementares nos veículos (quando realizados)
[ ] Coleta de informações com envolvidos, testemunhas e elementos relacionados ao acidente
[ ] Termo de Declaração do Envolvido anexado, se houver, ou justificativa para não preenchimento
[ ] Adoção das providências do item 108 do Manual em caso de indícios de crime doloso não relacionado ao acidente
[ ] Comunicação à chefia sobre eventuais problemas na via identificados, conforme item 195
[ ] Identificação e registro das trajetórias pré-colisão, colisão e pós-colisão dos veículos
[ ] Identificação e registro do(s) ponto(s) de impacto/colisão (sítios de colisão)
[ ] Consulta às tabelas dos Anexos A, B e C (quando aplicável)
[ ] Registro das evidências/vestígios que permitam a estimativa de velocidade dos veículos (ex: comprimento das marcas de frenagem, danos nos veículos, projeção/arremesso de vítimas, etc), consultando as tabelas dos Anexos quando aplicável
[ ] Descrição das condições da via, sinalização, iluminação, condições climáticas e outros fatores que possam ter influenciado na ocorrência do acidente
[ ] Registro das condições de visibilidade no momento do acidente (ofuscamento, chuva, neblina, etc)
[ ] Análise da compatibilidade entre as avarias/danos nos veículos e as lesões nas vítimas fatais com a dinâmica do acidente descrita
[ ] Registro de diligências realizadas para localização de envolvidos e testemunhas não identificados no local
[ ] Verificação do uso de cinto de segurança, capacete e dispositivos de retenção para crianças pelas vítimas
3. CONCLUSÃO  
[ ] Fatores contribuintes identificados com base nas evidências materiais constatadas
[ ] Fatores agravantes identificados com base nas evidências materiais constatadas
[ ] Fator determinante fundamentado em evidências materiais constatadas ou justificativa para impossibilidade de determinação
[ ] Ausência de presunções nas conclusões sobre fatores contribuintes, agravantes e determinantes
[ ] Ausência de termos valorativos (ex: imprudência, imperícia, negligência)
[ ] Coerência entre as conclusões e as informações apresentadas na dinâmica
[ ] Descrição da correlação entre as lesões das vítimas fatais e a dinâmica/cinemática do acidente
[ ] Indicação fundamentada da velocidade estimada dos veículos, sempre que possível, com base nos vestígios/evidências e consulta às tabelas do Manual
4. OBSERVAÇÕES
[ ] Informações complementares relevantes incluídas conforme item 284 do Manual
[ ] Registro das medidas administrativas adotadas
[ ] Registro da identificação das equipes de outros órgãos que atenderam a ocorrência ou não compareceram
[ ] Registro das ações de socorro às vítimas e possíveis situações de omissão de socorro  
[ ] Registro da destinação de objetos, pertences ou cargas sem responsável identificado
[ ] Registro de comunicação à Polícia Judiciária sobre crimes relacionados ao acidente ou constatados no atendimento da ocorrência
5. CROQUI
[ ] Croqui único representando toda a dinâmica do acidente
[ ] Elementos obrigatórios incluídos conforme item 274 do Manual 
[ ] Coerência entre croqui, levantamento do local e narrativa
[ ] Pontos de referência da amarração representados (origem do plano cartesiano ou pontos A e B)
[ ] Legenda dos elementos representados no croqui
[ ] Representação da interação entre as unidades de tráfego envolvidas em quadro à parte, quando relevante para elucidação da dinâmica
6. FOTOGRAFIAS  
[ ] Mínimo de 2 fotos panorâmicas do local nos sentidos da via, abrangendo todo o sítio do acidente
[ ] 4 fotos obrigatórias de cada veículo envolvido localizado (frente, traseira, laterais)
[ ] Fotos das vítimas fatais no local (sem exposição de imagens constrangedoras)  
[ ] Fotos detalhadas das lesões/ferimentos das vítimas fatais que possam auxiliar na análise da correlação trauma-dinâmica, sempre que possível
[ ] Fotos das vítimas fatais com sinalização/marcação das lesões, sempre que possível, para facilitar a análise da compatibilidade com a dinâmica
[ ] Fotos da identificação das vítimas fatais (rosto, tatuagens, cicatrizes, vestimentas ou outros elementos individualizadores), sempre que possível
[ ] Detalhes dos danos nos veículos
[ ] Detalhes das marcas/vestígios no pavimento  
[ ] Justificativa para eventual impossibilidade de inclusão de foto obrigatória
[ ] Fotos dos vestígios/evidências relacionados à dinâmica do acidente
[ ] Fotos de elementos relacionados a possíveis causas do acidente (problemas na via, sinalização, etc)
[ ] Fotos obtidas em eventual retorno ao local para complementação da perícia
[ ] Fotos da realização de teste de etilômetro e de sinais de embriaguez/uso de substâncias psicoativas pelos envolvidos, quando aplicável
[ ] Fotos de equipamentos de segurança dos veículos (cintos, air-bags, etc), quando possível, para verificar seu funcionamento
7. IDENTIFICAÇÃO DOS ENVOLVIDOS
[ ] Qualificação completa de condutores, vítimas fatais, vítimas feridas e testemunhas (nome, CPF, CNH, endereço, contato)
[ ] Consulta a sistemas para verificação de possíveis restrições dos envolvidos
[ ] Classificação dos veículos como "localizado" ou "não localizado", conforme item 64 do Manual
[ ] Registro de dados dos proprietários dos veículos, quando diferentes dos condutores
8. EXAME DE ALCOOLEMIA/OUTRAS SUBSTÂNCIAS
[ ] Registro da realização do teste de etilômetro e dos resultados obtidos, ou da recusa dos envolvidos em se submeter ao teste
[ ] Avaliação de sinais de alteração da capacidade psicomotora por outras substâncias
[ ] Resultado do exame de alcoolemia registrado no boletim ou recusa justificada no campo próprio
[ ] Registro de encaminhamento dos envolvidos para exame clínico/toxicológico, quando necessário
[ ] Coleta e registro de eventuais depoimentos de testemunhas que possam indicar consumo de álcool ou outras substâncias pelos envolvidos antes do acidente
9. AVALIAÇÃO DE DANOS NOS VEÍCULOS  
[ ] Formulário de avaliação de danos preenchido conforme Resolução CONTRAN vigente para cada veículo localizado
[ ] Marcação "NA" justificada individualmente para cada item não avaliado
[ ] Registro de eventual retirada do veículo sem avaliação de danos pelo proprietário/responsável 
[ ] Registro de danos pré-existentes sem relação com o acidente
[ ] Registro de danos decorrentes da própria dinâmica do acidente, da ação de resgate das vítimas ou da remoção dos veículos
[ ] Registro de danos causados por incêndio nos veículos, quando for o caso
10. DOCUMENTOS COMPLEMENTARES
[ ] Boletim de Atendimento Hospitalar (BAH) das vítimas anexado, quando disponível
[ ] Laudo/relatório do IML anexado, quando disponível  
[ ] Certidão de óbito das vítimas fatais anexada, quando disponível
[ ] Boletins de atendimento do SAMU, Corpo de Bombeiros, entre outros, anexados, quando disponíveis
[ ] Fichas de atendimento pré-hospitalar das equipes de resgate anexadas, quando disponíveis
[ ] Nota fiscal de remoção dos veículos anexada
[ ] Registro de remoção das vítimas fatais anexado
[ ] Termo de restituição de objetos/pertences anexado, quando aplicável
[ ] Cópia de eventual Inquérito Policial instaurado anexada
[ ] Cópia da CNH dos condutores anexada
[ ] Cópia do CRLV dos veículos anexada
[ ] Resultados de exames toxicológicos dos envolvidos anexados, quando realizados e disponíveis
11. CADEIA DE CUSTÓDIA
[ ] Etapas de coleta, acondicionamento, transporte, armazenamento e restituição das provas registradas adequadamente, conforme itens 266 e 267 do Manual  
[ ] Documentação da cadeia de custódia via processo SEI
[ ] Documentação fotográfica das etapas da cadeia de custódia
[ ] Justificativa para eventual não apreensão/coleta de vestígios relevantes
12. RECONSTITUIÇÃO
[ ] Realização de reconstituição do acidente, quando necessário, para elucidação da dinâmica
[ ] Descrição detalhada na narrativa dos procedimentos adotados na reconstituição e das conclusões obtidas
[ ] Registro fotográfico e em vídeo da reconstituição realizada
[ ] Juntada de croquis, diagramas, laudos ou outros documentos produzidos na reconstituição
[ ] Notificação prévia e convite formal à Polícia Judiciária e demais órgãos periciais para acompanhamento da reconstituição, sempre que realizada
13. ACIDENTES COM VEÍCULOS OFICIAIS OU EQUIPARADOS
[ ] Orientações dos itens 172 a 174 do Manual observadas
[ ] Registro da opção do condutor/gestor da frota pela não confecção de boletim, se for o caso
[ ] Comunicação ao órgão proprietário do veículo sobre a ocorrência do acidente e adoção das medidas administrativas cabíveis
[ ] Observação das orientações para veículos de concessionárias/permissionárias de serviços públicos, quando aplicável
16. COMUNICAÇÃO À POLÍCIA JUDICIÁRIA
[ ] Comunicação imediata realizada em caso de constatação de crimes relacionados direta ou indiretamente ao acidente, conforme itens 108 a 117 do Manual
[ ] Registro de eventual lavratura de TCO ou BOC pela própria firma, nos estados onde já implementado
[ ] Acionamento da perícia criminal para exames complementares, quando necessário
[ ] Acompanhamento e fornecimento de informações durante eventual investigação criminal sobre o acidente
17. PRESERVAÇÃO DO LOCAL DO ACIDENTE
[ ] Registro da classificação do local em preservado, parcialmente preservado ou desfeito, conforme item 186 do Manual
[ ] Justificativa para eventual não realização de procedimento obrigatório previsto no Manual em razão da necessidade de desfeita do local 
[ ] Isolamento e sinalização adequada do local para garantia da segurança viária e preservação de vestígios, conforme itens 123 a 137 do Manual
[ ] Registro de eventual alteração do local e suas consequências para as conclusões do boletim, conforme item 143
18. ACIONAMENTO DE PERÍCIA ESPECIALIZADA
[ ] Acionamento da equipe de perícia especializada nos casos de acidentes de relevância especial, conforme itens 155 a 168 do Manual
[ ] Designação formal do responsável pela elaboração do laudo pericial especializado ou parecer técnico
[ ] Acompanhamento e fornecimento de informações/documentos ao perito responsável pelo laudo/parecer
[ ] Adoção de procedimentos para garantia da cadeia de custódia de vestígios a serem periciados, conforme itens 266 e 267
19. DANOS AO PATRIMÔNIO PÚBLICO, MEIO AMBIENTE OU TERCEIROS  
[ ] Adoção das providências previstas nos itens 169 e 170 do Manual em caso de identificação de danos ao patrimônio público, ao meio ambiente ou ao patrimônio de terceiros
[ ] Descrição resumida dos danos ao patrimônio público, meio ambiente ou terceiros na narrativa, conforme item 284
[ ] Comunicação formal ao órgão responsável sobre os danos identificados
[ ] Documentação fotográfica dos danos constatados
[ ] Juntada de orçamentos ou notas fiscais dos reparos dos danos ao inquérito policial, quando disponíveis
20. ACIDENTES ENVOLVENDO TRANSPORTE DE CARGAS/PRODUTOS PERIGOSOS
[ ] Adoção das medidas previstas no Manual específico sobre atendimento de emergências com produtos perigosos
[ ] Registro da classificação, quantidade e condições da carga ou produto perigoso envolvido
[ ] Acionamento dos órgãos competentes (bombeiros, defesa civil, órgãos ambientais, etc)
[ ] Documentação fotográfica das embalagens, rótulos de risco e painéis de segurança, quando possível
[ ] Coleta e registro de informações sobre a origem e destino da carga/produto perigoso
[ ] Adoção de medidas para contenção de vazamentos e isolamento da área de risco
[ ] Acompanhamento e registro das ações de transbordo, descontaminação e liberação da pista
[ ] Juntada de documentos relativos à carga/produto perigoso (nota fiscal, ficha de emergência, envelope para transporte, etc)
21. ENCAMINHAMENTOS
[ ] Encaminhamento dos BAH, laudos e demais documentos relevantes anexados no boletim aos órgãos competentes
[ ] Encaminhamento dos veículos envolvidos para pátio, quando necessário, com o devido registro da medida administrativa 
[ ] Encaminhamento de cópia do boletim e do formulário de avaliação de danos aos órgãos de trânsito (DETRAN) para bloqueio dos veículos com danos de média ou grande monta, nos prazos estabelecidos pela Resolução CONTRAN
[ ] Encaminhamento de cópia do boletim à Polícia Judiciária, conforme item 366 do Manual
[ ] Encaminhamento de cópia do boletim ao Ministério Público, quando requisitado ou sempre que constatados indícios de crime doloso relacionado ao acidente
[ ] Encaminhamento de relatório sobre problemas na via identificados aos órgãos competentes (DNIT, concessionária, etc), conforme item 195
22. DADOS PARA AÇÕES DE PREVENÇÃO
[ ] Preenchimento de campos específicos do sistema com informações que possam subsidiar estudos e ações preventivas (condições da via, sinalização, condições climáticas, características do condutor, ações de fiscalização, etc)
[ ] Registro de sugestões de melhorias na via, sinalização, fiscalização ou outras medidas preventivas aplicáveis ao local do acidente
[ ] Preenchimento dos formulários de controle estatístico de acidentes no sistema informatizado, com os dados consolidados
23. OUTRAS VERIFICAÇÕES
[ ] Padrão de narrativa conforme Apêndice A1 do Manual
[ ] Revisão por um segundo policial (preferencialmente com curso de perícia), conforme itens 372 a 388 do Manual 
[ ] Prazo de 5 dias para confecção do boletim cumprido (prorrogável por mais 5 dias mediante justificativa)
[ ] Prazo de 5 dias para revisão do boletim cumprido (prorrogável por mais 5 dias mediante justificativa)  
[ ] boletim encerrado no sistema após revisão e correções, se necessárias
[ ] Processo de retificação aberto pela Chefia em caso de discordância relevante entre responsável e revisor, conforme item 384
24. ENCERRAMENTO E ARQUIVAMENTO
[ ] Impressão do boletim e assinatura pelo responsável e revisor  
[ ] Arquivamento digital do boletim no sistema informatizado 
[ ] Manutenção do boletim e documentos anexos arquivados por no mínimo 5 anos</code></section>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="trabalho" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[1. INTRODUÇÃO [ ] Data e hora da ocorrência [ ] Local (km, rodovia, sentido e município) [ ] Coordenadas geográficas (latitude e longitude) do ponto central do local do acidente [ ] Tipo de acidente (primeiro evento) [ ] Número de vítimas fatais, feridas (graves e leves) e ilesas [ ] Classificação do estado físico das vítimas conforme item 71 do Manual [ ] Identificação resumida dos veículos envolvidos (tipo, marca, modelo, cor predominante) [ ] Fase do dia (amanhecer, pleno dia, anoitecer, plena noite)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SRS within GitHub Actions</title><link href="https://ib.bsb.br/srs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SRS within GitHub Actions" /><published>2024-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-10T15:07:12+00:00</updated><id>https://ib.bsb.br/srs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ib.bsb.br/srs/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>source <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">https://github.com/riceissa/spaced-inbox</code></p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="spaced-inbox-documentation">Spaced Inbox Documentation</h1>

<blockquote>
  <p>This system provides spaced repetition for your notes written in plain text files, using a simple command-line interface and your favorite text editor. It aims to surface the most relevant and “exciting” notes at optimal intervals for long-term retention, while providing flexibility and control over your review process.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>1. Note Format</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Write your notes in a plain text file (e.g., <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">notes.txt</code>).</li>
  <li><strong>New Note Delimiters:</strong> Two blank lines, or a line containing at least three equals signs (and nothing else) like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">======</code>, signifies the start of a new note.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>2. Defining Inbox Files</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><strong><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">inbox_files.txt</code>:</strong> Create a file named <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">inbox_files.txt</code> to tell the script where your notes are located.</li>
  <li><strong>Format:</strong> Each line should follow this structure: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;short name&gt;&lt;tab&gt;&lt;file path&gt;</code>.
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Example:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">personal_notes /path/to/my/notes.txt</code></li>
      <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;short name&gt;</code>: A user-defined identifier for your inbox file, used by the script to distinguish between different inbox sources.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>3. Initializing and Updating the Database</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Initialization:</strong> Running <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">script.py</code> for the first time creates a SQLite database (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">data.db</code>) and imports your notes into it to manage the review schedule.</li>
  <li><strong>Subsequent Runs:</strong>  <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">script.py</code> performs the following actions on each subsequent execution:
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Import new notes:</strong> Detects and adds new notes from your inbox files that haven’t been imported previously.</li>
      <li><strong>Update note locations:</strong> If you’ve edited your inbox file and moved notes around (e.g., by adding or deleting lines), the script updates the corresponding line numbers in the database to ensure accurate navigation during review.</li>
      <li><strong>Handle soft-deletions:</strong> If you remove a note from an inbox file, the script detects its absence and marks it as “soft-deleted” in the database. This prevents the deleted note from appearing in future reviews unless you add it back to the inbox file.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>4. Daily Review Process</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Start a Review Session:</strong> Run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">script.py</code> to initiate a review session. The script will analyze your notes based on due dates, note states, and overdueness to select the most appropriate note for review.</li>
  <li><strong>Note Display:</strong> The script displays the beginning of the selected note along with its corresponding line numbers within the inbox file. This allows you to easily locate the note in your text editor.</li>
  <li><strong>Review in Editor:</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Open your preferred text editor.</li>
      <li>Navigate to the indicated line numbers to find the full note content.</li>
      <li>Review the note, make edits if necessary, or delete the note entirely from the inbox file if you no longer need it (this will trigger a soft-deletion on the next <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">script.py</code> run).</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Record Your Response (in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">script.py</code>’s prompt)</strong>
    <ul>
      <li><strong><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">[e]xciting</code>:</strong> Use this command if the note is particularly valuable, stimulating, or if you want to ensure you review it more frequently, even if it’s not the most overdue. <em>The script prioritizes “exciting” notes for selection, especially when they are overdue. The more overdue they get, the more likely they are to be chosen.</em></li>
      <li><strong><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">[i]nteresting</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">[y]eah</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">[l]ol</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">[m]eh</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">[c]ringe</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">[t]axing</code>:</strong> These commands represent varying degrees of positive or neutral feedback. They trigger the standard spaced repetition interval increase according to the SM2 algorithm, but <em>they don’t influence the note’s priority in the selection process beyond its regular due date</em>. The note state is recorded, which could potentially be used for refined note selection logic in future versions.</li>
      <li><strong><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">again</code>:</strong>  If you failed to recall the note’s content effectively, use this command. The review interval will be shortened (multiplied by 0.9), giving you another chance to learn it sooner. <em>The note state remains unchanged as an “again” response is considered a failure to recall, preventing a proper judgment of its emotional impact.</em></li>
      <li><strong><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">[r]eroll</code>:</strong> If you want to skip the currently displayed note without reviewing it, use this command to request a different note.</li>
      <li><strong><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">[q]uit</code>:</strong>  When you’re finished with your review session, use this command to exit the script.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>5. Spacing Algorithm</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Simplified SM2:</strong> The core of the scheduling algorithm is a simplified version of the <a href="https://gist.github.com/riceissa/1ead1b9881ffbb48793565ce69d7dbdd">Anki/SM2</a> algorithm, widely recognized for its effectiveness in spaced repetition learning.</li>
  <li><strong>Initial Interval:</strong>  The default starting interval for new notes is 50 days.</li>
  <li><strong>Subsequent Intervals:</strong>  Future review intervals are dynamically calculated based on your review responses (using the ease factor) and the SM2 algorithm. Specifically, the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">good_interval</code> function calculates the new interval by multiplying the current interval by the ease factor (which is always 300 in this implementation) and dividing by 100.</li>
  <li><strong>Note Prioritization (Not just due-date based):</strong>
    <ul>
      <li><strong>“Exciting” notes:</strong> Notes marked as “exciting” are highly prioritized for review, especially when they become overdue.  The more overdue an exciting note is, the more likely it is to be selected for review. This is achieved through a weighted probability selection process in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">get_exciting_note</code> function, where the weight is proportional to the square of the number of days the note is overdue.</li>
      <li><strong>Newly created notes:</strong> To reinforce initial learning, newly created notes that have not yet been reviewed receive a probability boost for selection during the 50-100 day period after their creation. This ensures you encounter new notes relatively soon after adding them. This is implemented in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">get_recent_unreviewed_note</code> function.</li>
      <li><strong>Regular reviewed notes:</strong> For notes that have been reviewed at least once (and are not marked as “exciting”), the script uses a weighted probability based on overdueness.  The more overdue a note is, the higher the chance it will be selected for review. This helps ensure you don’t completely neglect notes even if you skip reviews for a period of time. This is implemented in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">get_all_other_note</code> function, similar to how “exciting” notes are prioritized.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Ease Factor:</strong> The ease factor, a measure of how easily you recall a note, starts at 300% and remains constant throughout the note’s lifecycle in this implementation.</li>
  <li><strong>“Again” Interval Adjustment:</strong> When a note is marked as “again”, the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">again_interval</code> function is used to calculate the new interval, which is simply the current interval multiplied by 0.9.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Benefits</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Flexibility:</strong> Use your preferred text editor and any plain text format or markup language you like for your notes.</li>
  <li><strong>Control:</strong> You decide when and how many notes to review each day – there are no strict daily review quotas.</li>
  <li><strong>Intelligent Note Selection:</strong> The script’s note prioritization logic helps you focus on the most relevant and “exciting” notes, making your review sessions more efficient and engaging.</li>
  <li><strong>Editor Integration:</strong>  Seamlessly use your text editor of choice to review and edit notes.  (The optional <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">--external-program emacs</code> flag provides even deeper integration with Emacs, allowing automatic navigation to the selected note).</li>
  <li><strong>Non-Destructive:</strong> The script only reads from your inbox files and does not modify them in any way. Your notes remain entirely under your control.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="tools&gt;github&gt;estudos" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[source https://github.com/riceissa/spaced-inbox]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MLO URL schemes</title><link href="https://ib.bsb.br/mlo-url-schemes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MLO URL schemes" /><published>2024-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-25T20:19:25+00:00</updated><id>https://ib.bsb.br/mlo-url-schemes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ib.bsb.br/mlo-url-schemes/"><![CDATA[<p>mylifeorganized://open?view=TEST&amp;x-success=shortcuts://</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="tasks&gt;iphone" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[mylifeorganized://open?view=TEST&amp;x-success=shortcuts://]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RockChip devices</title><link href="https://ib.bsb.br/rockchip-devices/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RockChip devices" /><published>2024-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-18T13:04:22+00:00</updated><id>https://ib.bsb.br/rockchip-devices</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ib.bsb.br/rockchip-devices/"><![CDATA[<p>URL Source: https://sites.google.com/site/tweakradje/android/rockchip-device</p>

<p>Many Android devices use the RockChip soc these days. I have some using the ARM7 rk3066 dual core. I love it. It is fast but it must come with mali400 gpu. On this page I will try to explain how to customize these devices. Also some tools to do just that are added as downloads to the bottom of this page. I don’t use ClockWorkMod recovery much. All can be done with adb and some unix commands.</p>

<p>I use adb on this page. But adb sometimes doesn’t recognize newer devices. You can help it by creating a <strong>.android</strong> folder in your windows profile folder. Put <strong>adb_usb.ini</strong> in there with the USB VID of your device. RockChip has Vendor ID <strong>0x2207</strong>. See adb download below.</p>

<p>You device needs to be rooted (but most are from the factory).</p>

<p><strong>Backup Backup Backup</strong></p>

<p>The first thing you do before anything is create a proper backup of your new device. Just common sense.</p>

<p>Creating a backup of your device is very simple. You need an sdcard (or use internal /sdcard partition). From the Short Overview page we now know that Android roms are stored in mtd NAND partitions. So we need to get them to the PC.</p>

<p>After turning on your device manage to get an ADB connection working to your PC and follow these instructions:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>adb shell</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>su (if not pre-rooted)</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>stop</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>cat /proc/mtd</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>copy and paste the content of the output to a text file on your pc</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>mtd0: 00400000 00004000 “misc”</p>

<p>mtd1: 00800000 00004000 “kernel”</p>

<p>mtd2: 01000000 00004000 “boot”</p>

<p>mtd3: 01000000 00004000 “recovery”</p>

<p>mtd4: 18000000 00004000 “backup”</p>

<p>mtd5: 08000000 00004000 “cache”</p>

<p>mtd6: 20000000 00004000 “userdata”</p>

<p>mtd7: 00400000 00004000 “kpanic”</p>

<p>mtd8: 20000000 00004000 “system”</p>

<p>mtd9: 16bc00000 00004000 “user”</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>cat /dev/mtd/mtd0 &gt; /sdcard/mtd0_misc.img</p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>cat /dev/mtd/mtd1 &gt; /sdcard/mtd1_kernel.img</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>… do that for all mtd’s</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>exit</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><em><strong>Note:</strong></em> “user” is your internal /sdcard partition which size could be up to 12 Gb !!! Do not backup that one, this is the user installed packages and settings :)</p>

<p>Now back on your PC you need to copy them img’s to the PC with adb. Create a folder on your pc and use:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>adb pull /sdcard/mtd0_misc.img</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>adb pull /sdcard/mtd1_kernel.img</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>… do that for all mtd’s</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>For tablet you can also use ClockWorkMod Recovery to do it. I use CWMRecovery_RK3060_5.5.0.4 and flash it using flashtool (only flash recovery!)</p>

<p>Even easier is <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.h3r3t1c.onnandbup"></a> <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.h3r3t1c.onnandbup">NanDroid Backup</a>. You can install it from the PlayStore and perform a MTD backup on a live device. Choose CWM format.</p>

<p>Now you are safe as you can be and you can start changing some things on your device.</p>

<p><strong>Restoring</strong></p>

<p>This shows how to restore your device or flash it with other mtd partitions. There are tools for official RockChip roms. I will attach them below. But on this page I do not use them.</p>

<p>I will show how to restore mtd partitions with unix binary called <strong>flash_image</strong> on a running device. After that I will show how to do it on a dead device using the fastboot method. Fastboot is a low level Android device state which allows you to write mtd nand partitions too. The official RockChip flasher uses that Android device state too.</p>

<p><strong>With adb</strong></p>

<p>You need flash_image from below. And you need your original mtd images created earlier or other mtd images you want to try. Put your device in adb mode first.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>adb push flash_image /sdcard</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>adb push mtd0_misc.img /sdcard/mtd0_misc.img</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>adb push mtd1_kernel.img /sdcard/mtd1_kernel.img</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>… do that for all mtd’s</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>adb shell</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>su (if not pre-rooted)</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>stop</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>busybox cp /sdcard/flash_image /dev</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>cd /dev</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>chmod 777 fl*</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>./flash_image misc /sdcard/mtd0_misc.img</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>./flash_image kernel /sdcard/mtd1_kernel.img</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>… do that for all mtd’s</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>cd /data/dalvik-cache</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>rm *</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>sync</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>reboot</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>The first thing after the reboot is to do a factory reset to wipe the data partition. You will loose all user installed apps and data.</p>

<p><strong>With fastboot</strong></p>

<p>When your device is “bricked” you will not be able to get a proper adb connection. There is an escape: <strong>fastboot</strong>. How to enter fastboot on power up is different on every device. But you need to push and hold a button during boot or push and hold a paperclip in the hole. If in fastboot mode you will see a RK30SDK or similar device in your Windows hardware tree. It requires other USB drivers then regular adb. You can get it from the RockChipBatchTool below.</p>

<p>Fastboot is a <strong>Windows utility</strong>. All commands are done from the pc and are similar to that of the unix flash_image tool described earlier.</p>

<p>example: fastboot flash system mtd8_system.img</p>

<p><strong>Wendal.img: Unpack the firmare image (Rockchip_TOOLS)</strong></p>

<p>The Rockchip firmware image is packed as one img file containing these partitions (example RK3229 firmware):</p>

<p>boot.img</p>

<p>kernel.img</p>

<p>misc.img</p>

<p>recovery.img</p>

<p>resource.img</p>

<p>system.img</p>

<p>trust.img</p>

<p>uboot.img</p>

<p>You can Pack/Unpack it with the RK3066_IMG_Mod_Tool.zip you can download <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fronniehd%2Fandroid.projects.ec%2Ftree%2Fmaster%2FMK808%2FRockchip_TOOLS&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw3M2BDJvvk30-gBHBPUPBg2"></a> <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fronniehd%2Fandroid.projects.ec%2Ftree%2Fmaster%2FMK808%2FRockchip_TOOLS&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw3M2BDJvvk30-gBHBPUPBg2">here</a>.</p>

<p>Put your image in the Mod Tool folder and rename it to <strong>wendal.img</strong></p>

<p>Run the Runme.bat file to Unpack or Pack it. It will be unpacked in the <strong>temp\Image</strong> folder.</p>

<p><strong>Unpack the system.img</strong></p>

<p>You can unpack system.img with <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fforum.xda-developers.com%2Fshowthread.php%3Ft%3D1921399&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw0pXTRtpPu148sy-dHJFvOH"></a> <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fforum.xda-developers.com%2Fshowthread.php%3Ft%3D1921399&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw0pXTRtpPu148sy-dHJFvOH">EXT4 Unpacker</a> (or 7-zip now).</p>

<p><strong>System Mods</strong></p>

<p>You might want to change some things on your device’s system partition. Add some things to your build.prop ( better put them in your own /system/default.prop) or remove/add/update some apk’s.</p>

<p>The /system partition is readonly by default. Goto adb shell and mount the partition read-write: <strong>mount -o remount,rw /system</strong></p>

<p>Some interesting read from Finless <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.freaktab.com%2Fshowthread.php%3F287-RockChip-ROM-Building-Tips-and-Tricks-by-Finless&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw1PXsFNV1IynPdVXFxKAg-u"></a> <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.freaktab.com%2Fshowthread.php%3F287-RockChip-ROM-Building-Tips-and-Tricks-by-Finless&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw1PXsFNV1IynPdVXFxKAg-u">here</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Deep Sleep</strong></p>

<p>On the RK3066 tablets it is common that Deep Sleep system state is not happening. This is because of the ril daemon and a process that provides 3G USB dongle support. If you don’t use the 3G USB dongle you are better of with Deep Sleep. In standy your tablet battery last much longer.</p>

<p>The easiest way to kill this problem is to kill the rild process. This process starts as a service from the /init.rc file that belongs to the kernel.</p>

<p>service ril-daemon /system/bin/rild</p>

<p>class main</p>

<p>socket rild stream 660 root radio</p>

<p>socket rild-debug stream 660 radio system</p>

<p>user root</p>

<p>group radio cache inet misc audio sdcard_r sdcard_rw log</p>

<p>In a shell you can use this command to stop it each time after a reboot: <strong>stop ril-daemon</strong></p>

<p>Take a close look at that /init.rc file. You will see that /system/etc/install-recovery.sh is called there like this:</p>

<p>service flash_recovery /system/etc/install-recovery.sh</p>

<p>class main</p>

<p>oneshot</p>

<p>Now we can create a shell script <strong>/system/etc/install-recovery.sh</strong> that executes stop ril-daemon</p>

<p>#!/system/bin/sh</p>

<p>stop ril-daemon</p>

<p>Of course you can put into the install-recovery script what you want. Most setprop or sysctl commands or even use it for a semi init.d mechanism.</p>

<p><strong>Changing Wifi and BT drivers</strong></p>

<p>Leave alone all other mtd’s and only concentrate on /system. There are kernels that are in the boot.img but there are also devices that have a small boot.img and the kernel.img is used. In the kernel there is the low level driver for the hardware such as bluetooth, wifi and infrared remote control.</p>

<p>But the Android drivers are loaded by modules or libraries in the /system partition.</p>

<p>Check with dmesg command which hardware you have before you change the system.img. For the wifi chip you can also</p>

<p><strong>cat /sys/class/rkwifi/chip</strong> (like MT5931)</p>

<p>For changing the Wifi you need to replace or add with that from your original ROM</p>

<p>/system/lib/<strong>libhardware_legacy.so</strong> (loads proper driver module)</p>

<p>/system/lib/modules/xxxxx.ko (use <strong>lsmod</strong> to find the proper one that is loaded, in case of MT5931 <strong>wlan.ko</strong> is loaded )</p>

<p>/system/etc/firmware/yyyyy (where yyyyy is the file needed for your specific hardware loaded by xxxxx.ko, wlan.ko loads <strong>WIFI_RAM_CODE</strong> )</p>

<p>/system/bin/<strong>netd</strong></p>

<p>/system/bin/<strong>wpa_supplicant</strong></p>

<p>For changing Bluetooth you need to replace or add with that of your original ROM</p>

<p>/system/lib/<strong>libbluedroid.so</strong></p>

<p>/system/lib/<strong>libbluetooth_mtk.so</strong> (or other for specific hardware, this one it for MT6622 )</p>

<p>/system/etc/firmware/<strong>yyyyy</strong> (in this case /system/etc/firmware/<strong>MTK_MT6622_E2_Patch.nb0</strong> )</p>

<p>/system/bin/<strong>hciattach</strong></p>

<p>Of course you need to set the proper owner and permissions.</p>

<p>In /system/build.prop you sometimes find these lines to activate the options in the Android Settings app:</p>

<p>ro.version.radiocontrols=1</p>

<p>ro.version.bluetooth=1</p>

<p>ro.version.ethernet=1</p>

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>You find them by extracting the classes.dex from the Settings.apk file and do a: strings classes.dex</td>
      <td>find “ro.” (strings is sysinternals windows util)</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><strong>Enable multitouch rotate and tilt (jazzhand) on tablet</strong></p>

<p>On some Rockchip tablets you can only use multitouch zoom, not rotate or tilt. There is an easy fix on your rooted tablet.</p>

<p>Edit the /etc/permissions/android.hardware.touchscreen.multitouch file to read like this and write it back to /etc/permissions folder.</p>

<permissions>

<feature name="android.hardware.faketouch" />

<feature name="android.hardware.touchscreen" />

<feature name="android.hardware.touchscreen.multitouch" />

**<feature name="android.hardware.touchscreen.multitouch.distinct" />**

**<feature name="android.hardware.touchscreen.multitouch.jazzhand" />**

</permissions>

<p><strong>CrewRKTablets Tablet Roms</strong></p>

<p>CrewRKTablets is a german group that creates nice tablet roms for RockChip devices. <strong>You only need to flash the system.img and keep kernel</strong> (must be 3.0.8 or higher). They have made CM and JB/AOSP 4.x roms and can be found <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fcrewrktablets.arctablet.com%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw3U3PCyybtzxMl3XgqFwYaw"></a> <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fcrewrktablets.arctablet.com%2F&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw3U3PCyybtzxMl3XgqFwYaw">here</a>. On <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fforum.xda-developers.com%2Fshowthread.php%3Ft%3D2108704&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw2PkQmfm_NriXyDLgfVYQ2X"></a> <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fforum.xda-developers.com%2Fshowthread.php%3Ft%3D2108704&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw2PkQmfm_NriXyDLgfVYQ2X">XDA</a> there are some threads too. Try <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fcrewrktablets.arctablet.com%2F%3Fp%3D2315&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw2eaoB8zz_7fVoY8LVMWUAg"></a> <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fcrewrktablets.arctablet.com%2F%3Fp%3D2315&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw2eaoB8zz_7fVoY8LVMWUAg">AOSP 4.2.2 v3.3</a> first (fastest).</p>

<p>But not always your Wifi/Bluetooth/Rotation sensor (<a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fforum.xda-developers.com%2Fshowpost.php%3Fp%3D46532663%26postcount%3D619&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw0cBeoX-MhH8YPcEDYA0KXD">fix</a>) is supported by default. But you can find fixes there or on the xda thread.</p>

<p>The rotation sensor is <strong>/system/lib/hw/sensors/sensors.rk30board.so</strong></p>

<p>Sometimes you internal SD card is not recognized. That can be <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fforum.xda-developers.com%2Fshowpost.php%3Fp%3D48004974%26postcount%3D736&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw1dlU6Hyw_wCPJZps25-oCa"></a> <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fforum.xda-developers.com%2Fshowpost.php%3Fp%3D48004974%26postcount%3D736&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw1dlU6Hyw_wCPJZps25-oCa">fixed</a> with reformatting it FAT32 directly again after flashing.</p>

<p>If e.g. your internal sdcard (mtd called user) is mtd9:</p>

<p>0x0000eb400000-0x0003db800000 : “user” mtd9 /sdcard (FAT) internal</p>

<p>mkdosfs -F 32 /dev/block/mtdblock9</p>

<p>and reboot.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="hardware" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[URL Source: https://sites.google.com/site/tweakradje/android/rockchip-device]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Linux mobile OS</title><link href="https://ib.bsb.br/linux-mobile-os/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linux mobile OS" /><published>2024-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-23T02:24:13+00:00</updated><id>https://ib.bsb.br/linux-mobile-os</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ib.bsb.br/linux-mobile-os/"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Ubuntu Touch</strong></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>LineageOS</strong>: A free and open-source operating system for smartphones and tablets, derived from the popular custom ROM CyanogenMod. It is known for its privacy and security features, lightweight nature, and lack of ads and tracking. LineageOS is highly customizable and supports a wide range of devices.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>GrapheneOS</strong>: A privacy and security-focused mobile OS with Android app compatibility. It emphasizes research and development in privacy and security technologies, offering features like over-the-air (OTA) updates, no tracking, and ad-free usage. It is particularly suitable for users who prioritize security.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>/e/ (formerly eelo)</strong>: A fork of LineageOS that aims to be completely free of Google services. It focuses on user privacy and simplicity, integrating features like Nextcloud for cloud sync and being ad-free. It provides a de-Googled experience while maintaining compatibility with Android apps.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>CalyxOS</strong>: Another privacy-focused mobile OS designed to prevent tracking by governments and corporations. It offers features like OTA updates, ad-free usage, and no tracking. CalyxOS is built on the Android Open Source Project (AOSP) and includes additional security enhancements.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Replicant</strong>: A fully free Android distribution emphasizing freedom, privacy, and security. It replaces or avoids every proprietary component, making it a strong alternative for users who value software freedom. Replicant is focused on providing a completely open-source mobile experience.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Sailfish OS</strong>: Developed by Jolla, Mer, the Sailfish Alliance, and community members, Sailfish OS is a continuation of the MeeGo OS. It offers Android app support and Microsoft Exchange compatibility. Sailfish OS is known for its smooth performance and unique user interface.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Plasma Mobile</strong>: An open-source user interface for mobile devices developed by the KDE community. It transforms phones into fully open hacking devices, similar to PCs, and is privacy-focused and ad-free. Plasma Mobile is built on top of the KDE Plasma desktop environment.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>postmarketOS</strong>: Extends Alpine Linux to run on smartphones and other mobile devices. It is security-oriented, lightweight, and privacy-focused. postmarketOS aims to provide long-term support and is suitable for users who want a Linux-based alternative to Android.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Mobian</strong>: Known as “Debian for Mobile,” Mobian is available for phones and tablets and is based on Debian. It aims to bring the stability and reliability of Debian to mobile devices.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Manjaro ARM</strong>: An ARM version of the Arch Linux-based Manjaro distro, utilizing the Plasma Mobile interface. It supports desktop Plasma apps and widgets, as well as Ubuntu Touch apps. Manjaro ARM is known for its rolling release model and user-friendly experience.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Arch Linux ARM</strong>: Similar to Manjaro ARM, this distro also uses the Plasma Mobile desktop and is suitable for devices like the PinePhone and PinePhone Pro. It provides a highly customizable and lightweight environment.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>openSUSE</strong>: Utilizing a rolling release system, openSUSE Tumbleweed is available for the PinePhone. It uses the Plasma Mobile interface and supports a wide range of apps for an open-source mobile experience. openSUSE is known for its robust package management and stability.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="linux," /><category term="software&gt;mobile" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu Touch]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PageFind with Jekyll</title><link href="https://ib.bsb.br/pagefind-with-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PageFind with Jekyll" /><published>2024-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-23T00:31:10+00:00</updated><id>https://ib.bsb.br/pagefind-with-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ib.bsb.br/pagefind-with-jekyll/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="understanding-the-components"><strong>Understanding the Components</strong></h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>PageFind:</strong> A powerful search library designed for static websites, offering a fast and efficient search experience without server-side components.</li>
  <li><strong>Jekyll Plugin:</strong> A custom Ruby plugin (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_plugins/pagefind.rb</code>) that automatically triggers PageFind indexing after your Jekyll site is built.</li>
  <li><strong>GitHub Actions:</strong> A CI/CD platform that automates the build and deployment process, ensuring your site is updated whenever changes are pushed to your repository.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="step-by-step-implementation"><strong>Step-by-Step Implementation</strong></h4>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Create the Search Page:</strong><br />
Add a new Markdown file named <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">search.md</code> to your Jekyll site’s <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pages</code> directory. This file will contain the search interface:</p>

    <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nn">---</span>
<span class="na">layout</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">default</span>
<span class="na">title</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">Site Search</span>
<span class="na">permalink</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">/search/</span>
<span class="nn">---</span>
   
<span class="nt">&lt;link</span> <span class="na">href=</span><span class="s">"/pagefind/pagefind-ui.css"</span> <span class="na">rel=</span><span class="s">"stylesheet"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;script </span><span class="na">src=</span><span class="s">"/pagefind/pagefind-ui.js"</span><span class="nt">&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</span>
   
<span class="nt">&lt;h1</span> <span class="na">style=</span><span class="s">"text-align: center"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>Site Search<span class="nt">&lt;/h1&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;div</span> <span class="na">id=</span><span class="s">"search"</span><span class="nt">&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;p</span> <span class="na">style=</span><span class="s">"text-align: center; font-size: 0.7em"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>Powered by <span class="nt">&lt;a</span> <span class="na">target=</span><span class="s">"_blank"</span> <span class="na">href=</span><span class="s">"https://pagefind.app/"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>PageFind<span class="nt">&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</span>
   
<span class="nt">&lt;script&gt;</span>
    window.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', (event) =&gt; {
        new PagefindUI({ element: "#search", showSubResults: true });
    });
<span class="nt">&lt;/script&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Configure Jekyll:</strong><br />
Update your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_config.yml</code> file to include the custom PageFind plugin:</p>

    <div class="language-yaml highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="na">plugins</span><span class="pi">:</span>
  <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="s">jekyll-sitemap</span>
  <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="s">jekyll-gist</span>
  <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="s">jekyll-feed</span>
  <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="s">jekyll-toc</span>
  <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="s">kramdown</span>
  <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="s">jekyll-sitemap</span>
  <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="s">./_plugins/pagefind.rb</span>
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Create the PageFind Plugin:</strong><br />
Create a new directory named <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_plugins</code> at the root of your Jekyll project and add a file named <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pagefind.rb</code> with the following content:</p>

    <div class="language-ruby highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="no">Jekyll</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="no">Hooks</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">register</span> <span class="ss">:site</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="ss">:post_write</span> <span class="k">do</span> <span class="o">|</span><span class="n">site</span><span class="o">|</span>
  <span class="nb">system</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">"pagefind --source '_site'"</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Configure PageFind:</strong><br />
Create a file named <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pagefind.yml</code> in your root directory to configure PageFind’s behavior:</p>

    <div class="language-yaml highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="na">source</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">_site</span>
<span class="na">bundle_dir</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">_pagefind</span>
<span class="na">split_pages_on</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s2">"</span><span class="s">h2"</span>
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Set up GitHub Actions:</strong><br />
Create a new file named <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.github/workflows/deploy.yml</code> in your repository with the following content. This setup will install PageFind during the deployment process, eliminating the need for a local installation:</p>

    <div class="language-yaml highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="na">name</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">GitHub Pages</span>

<span class="na">on</span><span class="pi">:</span>
  <span class="na">push</span><span class="pi">:</span>
    <span class="na">branches</span><span class="pi">:</span>
      <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="s">main</span>  <span class="c1"># Change this to your default branch if it's not 'main'</span>

<span class="na">jobs</span><span class="pi">:</span>
  <span class="na">build</span><span class="pi">:</span>
    <span class="na">runs-on</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">ubuntu-latest</span>

    <span class="na">steps</span><span class="pi">:</span>
    <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="na">name</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">Checkout repository</span>
      <span class="na">uses</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">actions/checkout@v2</span>

    <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="na">name</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">Setup Ruby</span>
      <span class="na">uses</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">ruby/setup-ruby@v1</span>
      <span class="na">with</span><span class="pi">:</span>
        <span class="na">ruby-version</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s1">'</span><span class="s">3.0'</span>

    <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="na">name</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">Install Jekyll and Bundler</span>
      <span class="na">run</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="pi">|</span>
        <span class="s">gem install jekyll bundler</span>
        <span class="s">bundle install</span>

    <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="na">name</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">Install Node.js</span>
      <span class="na">uses</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">actions/setup-node@v2</span>
      <span class="na">with</span><span class="pi">:</span>
        <span class="na">node-version</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s1">'</span><span class="s">14'</span>

    <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="na">name</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">Install PageFind</span>
      <span class="na">run</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">npm install -g @pagefind/core</span>

    <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="na">name</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">Build site with Jekyll</span>
      <span class="na">run</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">bundle exec jekyll build</span>

    <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="na">name</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">Run PageFind indexing</span>
      <span class="na">run</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">pagefind --source _site</span>

    <span class="pi">-</span> <span class="na">name</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">Deploy to GitHub Pages</span>
      <span class="na">uses</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">peaceiris/actions-gh-pages@v3</span>
      <span class="na">with</span><span class="pi">:</span>
        <span class="na">github_token</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">$</span>
        <span class="na">publish_dir</span><span class="pi">:</span> <span class="s">./_site</span>
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
</ol>

<h4 id="explanation-and-key-considerations"><strong>Explanation and Key Considerations</strong></h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_plugins/pagefind.rb</code>:</strong> This plugin ensures that PageFind indexes your site content after each build.</li>
  <li><strong><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pagefind.yml</code>:</strong> This file configures PageFind, specifying the source directory, output directory, and content splitting behavior.</li>
  <li><strong><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.github/workflows/deploy.yml</code>:</strong> This workflow automates the entire process, building your Jekyll site, running PageFind indexing, and deploying the final output to GitHub Pages.</li>
  <li><strong><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pagefind-entry.json</code>:</strong> This file, generated by PageFind during indexing, is crucial for the search functionality. Ensure it’s correctly generated and located in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_pagefind</code> directory.</li>
  <li><strong>CSS Customization:</strong> Include and customize the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pagefind-modular-ui.css</code> file to style the search interface according to your website’s design.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="github&gt;jekyll" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding the Components]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Arm Tendinitis</title><link href="https://ib.bsb.br/arm-tendinitis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arm Tendinitis" /><published>2024-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-13T21:04:28+00:00</updated><id>https://ib.bsb.br/arm-tendinitis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ib.bsb.br/arm-tendinitis/"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><strong>Tendinitis</strong>: Inflammation of the tendons, which can cause pain and stiffness. However, tendinitis typically affects specific areas rather than the entire arm.</li>
  <li><strong>Carpal Tunnel Syndrome</strong>: Compression of the median nerve in the wrist, leading to pain, numbness, and tingling in the thumb, index, middle, and ring fingers. This can sometimes extend up the arm.</li>
  <li><strong>Cubital Tunnel Syndrome</strong>: Compression of the ulnar nerve at the elbow, causing pain and tingling in the ring and pinky fingers, which can extend up the forearm.</li>
  <li><strong>Radial Tunnel Syndrome</strong>: Compression of the radial nerve, which can cause pain from the elbow to the hand, often mistaken for tennis elbow.</li>
  <li><strong>Thoracic Outlet Syndrome</strong>: Compression of nerves or blood vessels between the collarbone and the first rib, leading to pain and numbness in the arm and hand.</li>
  <li><strong>Cervical Radiculopathy</strong>: Nerve compression in the neck, which can cause pain, numbness, and weakness radiating down the arm.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="symptoms-to-watch-for">Symptoms to Watch For</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Pain</strong>: Along the entire arm, especially when using the mouse or cellphone.</li>
  <li><strong>Stiffness</strong>: In the thumb and other parts of the arm.</li>
  <li><strong>Shocks</strong>: Sudden, sharp pain or tingling sensations.</li>
  <li><strong>Tremors</strong>: Involuntary movements, particularly in the thumb.</li>
  <li><strong>Numbness or Tingling</strong>: In the fingers or arm.</li>
  <li><strong>Weakness</strong>: Difficulty in gripping or lifting objects.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="immediate-steps">Immediate Steps</h2>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Rest and Avoid Aggravating Activities</strong>: Limit the use of the mouse and cellphone.</li>
  <li><strong>Ergonomic Adjustments</strong>: Use ergonomic tools to reduce strain.</li>
  <li><strong>Ice and Compression</strong>: Apply ice packs and use compression sleeves.</li>
  <li><strong>Anti-inflammatory Medications</strong>: Over-the-counter NSAIDs like ibuprofen.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="when-to-see-a-doctor">When to See a Doctor</h2>

<p>Given the complexity and severity of your symptoms, it is crucial to consult a healthcare professional for a thorough evaluation. They may recommend:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Physical Examination</strong>: To assess the range of motion, strength, and areas of tenderness.</li>
  <li><strong>Imaging Studies</strong>: X-rays, MRI, or ultrasound to visualize the affected areas.</li>
  <li><strong>Nerve Conduction Studies</strong>: To evaluate nerve function and identify any compression or damage.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="possible-treatments">Possible Treatments</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Physical Therapy</strong>: Tailored exercises and stretches to improve flexibility and strength.</li>
  <li><strong>Medications</strong>: Anti-inflammatory drugs, pain relievers, or corticosteroid injections.</li>
  <li><strong>Ergonomic Adjustments</strong>: Modifications to your workspace and daily activities.</li>
  <li><strong>Surgery</strong>: In severe cases, surgical intervention may be necessary to relieve nerve compression.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="weight-lifting-program-for-tendinitis-recovery">Weight Lifting Program for Tendinitis Recovery</h2>

<p>To develop a daily weight lifting program for tendinitis recovery, it is essential to understand the unique characteristics and recovery needs of tendons compared to muscles. Here is a structured program based on the FITT Principle (Frequency, Intensity, Type, Time):</p>

<h3 id="frequency">Frequency</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Perform tendon exercises 2 times a day, separated by at least 6 hours, for 3-4 days per week.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="intensity">Intensity</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Use a heavy weight that allows you to complete just 8-15 repetitions per set (3 sets of 8-15 reps).</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="type">Type</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Execute the exercises at a slow tempo, taking 3-4 seconds for both the upward and downward movements.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="time">Time</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Limit the tendon exercises to 5-10 minutes with short rest periods of 20-30 seconds between sets.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="example-exercises">Example Exercises</h3>

<h4 id="1-slow-heavy-squats">1. Slow, Heavy Squats</h4>
<ul>
  <li><strong>How to Perform</strong>: Stand with feet shoulder-width apart, hold a weight (dumbbell or barbell) at your shoulders or sides. Slowly lower into a squat position over 3-4 seconds, then rise back up over 3-4 seconds.</li>
  <li><strong>Reps/Sets</strong>: 3 sets of 8-15 reps.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="2-eccentric-wrist-flexion">2. Eccentric Wrist Flexion</h4>
<ul>
  <li><strong>How to Perform</strong>: Hold a light weight (1-2 pounds) in your hand with your palm facing up. Slowly lower the weight down over 3-4 seconds, then use your other hand to help lift it back up.</li>
  <li><strong>Reps/Sets</strong>: 3 sets of 8-15 reps.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="3-eccentric-wrist-extension">3. Eccentric Wrist Extension</h4>
<ul>
  <li><strong>How to Perform</strong>: Hold a light weight with your palm facing down. Slowly lower the weight down over 3-4 seconds, then use your other hand to help lift it back up.</li>
  <li><strong>Reps/Sets</strong>: 3 sets of 8-15 reps.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="4-calf-raises">4. Calf Raises</h4>
<ul>
  <li><strong>How to Perform</strong>: Stand on a step with your heels hanging off the edge. Slowly raise your heels up over 3-4 seconds, then lower them back down over 3-4 seconds.</li>
  <li><strong>Reps/Sets</strong>: 3 sets of 8-15 reps.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="5-bicep-curls">5. Bicep Curls</h4>
<ul>
  <li><strong>How to Perform</strong>: Use a light weight (5-8 pounds). Stand up straight and hold the weight with your palm facing up. Slowly curl the weight up towards your shoulder over 3-4 seconds, then lower it back down over 3-4 seconds.</li>
  <li><strong>Reps/Sets</strong>: 3 sets of 8-15 reps.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="farmers-walk-and-tendinitis">Farmers Walk and Tendinitis</h2>

<h3 id="benefits-of-farmers-walk">Benefits of Farmers Walk</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Grip Strength</strong>: The Farmers Walk is excellent for improving grip strength, which can be beneficial for various daily activities and other exercises.</li>
  <li><strong>Forearm Strength</strong>: It helps in building both forearm size and strength, which can support the muscles and tendons in your arms.</li>
  <li><strong>Postural Strength</strong>: Enhances postural stability and control, which can help in maintaining proper alignment and reducing strain on tendons.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="considerations-for-tendinitis">Considerations for Tendinitis</h3>

<p>While the Farmers Walk has numerous benefits, it is crucial to consider how it impacts tendinitis, especially given your symptoms of pain, stiffness, and nerve involvement.</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Repetitive Strain</strong>: The repetitive gripping and carrying motion can potentially exacerbate tendinitis if not performed correctly or if the weights are too heavy.</li>
  <li><strong>Nerve Compression</strong>: Given your symptoms of shocks and tremors, there might be nerve involvement. The Farmers Walk could potentially increase pressure on the nerves if not done with proper form and weight management.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="recommended-approach">Recommended Approach</h3>

<h4 id="start-light-and-gradual">Start Light and Gradual</h4>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Light Weights</strong>: Begin with lighter weights to avoid excessive strain on your tendons and nerves.</li>
  <li><strong>Short Distances</strong>: Start with shorter distances and gradually increase as your strength and endurance improve.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="focus-on-form">Focus on Form</h4>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Proper Grip</strong>: Ensure you are gripping the weights correctly to avoid unnecessary strain on your wrists and forearms.</li>
  <li><strong>Posture</strong>: Maintain an upright posture with shoulders back and core engaged to distribute the load evenly.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="complementary-exercises-and-massages">Complementary Exercises and Massages</h4>

<p>In addition to the Farmers Walk, incorporate specific exercises and massages to alleviate symptoms and strengthen the affected muscles.</p>

<h3 id="exercises">Exercises</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Wrist Flexor and Extensor Stretches</strong>
    <ul>
      <li><strong>How to Perform</strong>: Extend your arm with the palm up/down and gently pull your fingers back with the other hand.</li>
      <li><strong>Duration</strong>: Hold for 15-30 seconds.</li>
      <li><strong>Repetitions</strong>: Repeat 2-4 times.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Eccentric Wrist Flexion and Extension</strong>
    <ul>
      <li><strong>How to Perform</strong>: Use a light weight, slowly lower it down over 3-4 seconds, and use the other hand to lift it back up.</li>
      <li><strong>Repetitions</strong>: 10-15 reps.</li>
      <li><strong>Sets</strong>: 2-3 sets.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Thumb Flexion and Extension</strong>
    <ul>
      <li><strong>How to Perform</strong>: Gently bend your thumb towards your palm and extend it back out.</li>
      <li><strong>Repetitions</strong>: 10-15 reps.</li>
      <li><strong>Sets</strong>: 2-3 sets.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="massages">Massages</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Forearm Massage</strong>
    <ul>
      <li><strong>How to Perform</strong>: Use your opposite hand or a massage tool to apply gentle pressure in circular motions along the forearm.</li>
      <li><strong>Duration</strong>: 5-10 minutes.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Thumb and Wrist Massage</strong>
    <ul>
      <li><strong>How to Perform</strong>: Gently massage the base of your thumb and wrist using circular motions.</li>
      <li><strong>Duration</strong>: 5-10 minutes.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Ice Massage</strong>
    <ul>
      <li><strong>How to Perform</strong>: Rub ice over the affected area in circular motions.</li>
      <li><strong>Duration</strong>: 5-10 minutes.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<h2 id="prognosis-and-recovery">Prognosis and Recovery</h2>

<h3 id="is-it-possible-to-be-cured">Is It Possible to Be Cured?</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Early Intervention</strong>: If treated early and appropriately, tendinitis and related conditions can often be fully resolved with conservative treatments such as rest, physical therapy, and ergonomic adjustments.</li>
  <li><strong>Chronic Conditions</strong>: Chronic conditions may take longer to recover, but with consistent treatment, significant improvement is possible.</li>
  <li><strong>Permanent Damage</strong>: Severe cases with extensive tendon or nerve damage may result in some degree of permanent impairment, but this is less common.</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="saúde" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tendinitis: Inflammation of the tendons, which can cause pain and stiffness. However, tendinitis typically affects specific areas rather than the entire arm. Carpal Tunnel Syndrome: Compression of the median nerve in the wrist, leading to pain, numbness, and tingling in the thumb, index, middle, and ring fingers. This can sometimes extend up the arm. Cubital Tunnel Syndrome: Compression of the ulnar nerve at the elbow, causing pain and tingling in the ring and pinky fingers, which can extend up the forearm. Radial Tunnel Syndrome: Compression of the radial nerve, which can cause pain from the elbow to the hand, often mistaken for tennis elbow. Thoracic Outlet Syndrome: Compression of nerves or blood vessels between the collarbone and the first rib, leading to pain and numbness in the arm and hand. Cervical Radiculopathy: Nerve compression in the neck, which can cause pain, numbness, and weakness radiating down the arm.]]></summary></entry></feed>